Thank you.
谢谢。
¶¶
¶¶
I don't know.
我不知道。
Thank you.
谢谢。
¶¶
¶¶
All right.
好的。
Welcome back to the Ethereum Protocol Fellowship.
欢迎回到以太坊协议奖学金。
This is our final session today,
这是我们今天的最后会议，
week 10 on the research track.
研究轨道上的第10周。
And we have Francesco with us today
我们今天有弗朗切斯科
to talk about some consensus upgrades.
谈论一些共识升级。
Yeah, so I'll go ahead and let Mario
是的，所以我继续让马里奥
give him a more proper introduction,
给他一个更适当的介绍，
but happy to have you here, Francesco.
但是很高兴有你在这里，弗朗切斯科。
And thanks for everyone for tuning in.
并感谢大家的调整。
Thank you so much for being here, Francesco.
非常感谢您在这里，Francesco。
You might not realize, but you are a very special guest
您可能没有意识到，但是您是一个非常特别的客人
because it's the very, very last talk of the whole EPF study group
因为这是整个EPF研究小组的最后一次讨论
and especially the research track.
尤其是研究轨道。
And yeah, we have Francesco here today because he's a researcher.
是的，我们今天在这里有Francesco，因为他是研究员。
Francesco studied mathematics and joined EF a few years ago.
弗朗切斯科（Francesco）学习了数学，并在几年前加入了EF。
Since then, he's been working mostly on consensus,
从那以后，他一直在共识，
a lot of interesting consensus research papers and proposals that came from Francesco and his
来自Francesco及其他的许多有趣的共识研究论文和建议
colleagues. But today he will specifically be talking about fork choice, give us a recap of
同事。但是今天他将特别谈论叉子的选择，给我们一个回顾
how the Gaspar even works and what are the upgrades coming, like the single-slot finality,
Gaspar如何工作以及升级是什么，例如单槽终结性，
which is his field. So yeah, thank you so much for being here. I hope you can hear us all well
这是他的领域。是的，非常感谢您在这里。希望你能听到我们的声音
and we can hear you too yeah yeah i can hear you can you hear me awesome yeah all good so yeah uh
我们也能听到你的声音，是的，我可以听到你能听到我很棒的是，很好，是的
the stage is yours uh you can share your slides here so if you have any presentation link go for
阶段是您的嗯，您可以在这里共享幻灯片
it now and uh we can start in a second yeah um let me uh first share a link to slides and then
现在，我们可以从第二秒开始，是的，嗯，让我第一次共享幻灯片的链接
and then I'll just share screen.
然后我只分享屏幕。
Do you see the presentation screen?
您看到演示屏幕吗？
it here.
它在这里。
Okay.
好的。
Awesome.
惊人的。
So, yeah, I guess one thing I'm not entirely sure about, because I haven't done this before
所以，是的，我想我不确定的一件事，因为我以前从未做过
or followed, is it possible to interact with people?
还是随之而来的是，可以与人互动吗？
Can people ask questions?
人们可以问问题吗？
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
是的，是的。
So people will ask questions in our Discord.
因此，人们会在我们的不和谐中提出问题。
I can send it if you have extra space to watch it, but when they ask questions, we can make
如果您有额外的空间观看，我可以发送它，但是当他们提出问题时，我们可以做到
a pause.
暂停。
We will just ask you.
我们只会问你。
So after each segment, give us a minute for potential questions, and we will chime in
因此，在每个细分市场之后，请给我们一分钟的潜在问题，我们将在
with, read what people are asking.
用，阅读人们在问什么。
Okay.
好的。
Yeah.
是的。
I mean, if you can, yeah, if you can do that.
我的意思是，如果可以的话，是的，如果可以的话。
We can handle it.
我们可以处理。
Yeah.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
Then, yeah, I guess I'll just go ahead and start and kind of start the recap of Gaspar.
然后，是的，我想我会继续前进，开始重新开始加斯帕。
I'm not entirely sure how much people know about the protocol or things like that.
我不确定人们对协议或类似事物有多少了解。
So I guess if you get early feedback about, you know, this being too slow or like, you
因此，我想如果您会得到早期的反馈，您知道，这太慢或类似，您
everything is clear or that I need to slow down or whatever, just let me know
一切都很清楚，或者我需要放慢脚步或其他任何东西，请让我知道
early that would be helpful. So Gaspar is just the name of our protocol it comes from
早些时候这将是有帮助的。因此，gaspar只是我们协议的名称，它来自
it comes from the two components that characterize it which are
它来自表征它的两个组件
LMD ghost, that's just where the g comes from, and GasparFFG. Let's first dive
LMD幽灵，这就是G的来源，而Gasparffg。让我们第一次潜水
into the ghost part because that's kind of the maybe the most critical component um so ghost
进入幽灵部分，因为那是最关键的组成部分，所以鬼
stands for previous heaviest heaviest observed sub-3 and basically this already describes what
代表以前最重的最重观察到的Sub-3，基本上已经描述了什么
ghost actually does like as an algorithm and essentially this is like a force choice algorithm
Ghost实际上确实喜欢作为一种算法，从本质上讲，这就像一种力选择算法
so it's an algorithm that allows you given uh basically a block tree to find the head of the
因此，这是一种算法，允许您基本上给出一个块树来找到
chain so the what you want to consider as the canonical chain essentially uh in case there are
链所以您想将其视为规范链本质上是嗯，以防万一
forks and ghost originally operates just on blocks so here there's no boats there's just blocks
叉子和幽灵最初仅在街区上运行，所以这里没有船只只有块
um so basically the way it works it is uh you just run through the block tree
嗯，基本上它的工作方式是您刚刚穿过块树
when there's no forks you just keep going uh once you get to a fork you basically choose the
当没有叉子时，一旦到达叉子，您就会继续前进，您基本上会选择
heaviest and so that yeah the the first part is the greedy part where you just just keep going
最重，是的，第一部分是贪婪的部分，您只是继续前进
like really and you make a choice whenever you have to um and the heaviest part is that you uh
就像真的一样，您在必须的时候做出选择，最重的部分是您
or heaviest sub-tree part, is that once you do have to make a choice at a fork, you just choose
或最重的子树一部分是，一旦您必须在叉子上做出选择，只需选择
the heaviest sub-tree. So in this case, the sub-tree above has five blocks and the one below
最重的子树。因此，在这种情况下，上面的子树有五个街区，下面有一个街区
has four, so you choose the highest one, and then you keep going this way, and you eventually get
有四个
to have the chain. So this was originally basically proposed as an alternative to longest
拥有链。因此，这最初是基本提出的，以替代最长
chain, so you can see that in the case of longest chain, let's say that there's a period of maybe
链，因此您可以看到，在最长的链中，假设有一段时间
network problems and the honest chain or honest kind of uh well the honest participants basically
网络问题以及诚实的链条或诚实的嗯，诚实的参与者基本上是
construct a forked block tree so it's like green part um whereas the there might be like some
构建一棵分叉的块树，所以就像绿色的部分，而可能有一些
adversarial chain which in this case is this red one that's kind of hidden um and uh yeah basically
对抗链，在这种情况下，这种红色是隐藏的，嗯，是的，基本上是
not revealed by the adversary and this is actually just a chain uh it's it's not fourth maybe it's
对手没有透露，这实际上只是一条链，这不是第四，也许是
literally just one party that's that's doing this like one minor uh at the time uh and then yeah in
从字面上看，这就是一个聚会，就像当时的一个未成年人一样，然后是的
not this chain this would be the canonical chain like once it's revealed
这不是这个链条，这将是一条规范的链条，就像它被揭示
uh this red one oh by the way can you see my uh pointer
嗯，这个红色的一个哦，顺便说一下，你能看到我的指针
uh we don't see your cursor if you know it's what you mean uh can you can you move up we can see we
嗯，如果您知道这是您的意思，我们不会看到您的光标
can say yeah it's a bit small but okay it'll do but yeah anyway so basically this chain would be
可以说是的，有点小，但是可以，但是是的，无论如何，这基本上是这个链
the the canonical one but the wheat ghost it's it's the sub tree above that uh so yeah in this
规范的人，而不是小麦鬼，它是上方的子树，呃，是的
case this block would be the canonical one. As it turns out it actually also works better
案例这个块将是规范的。事实证明它实际上也更好
once you transition to having votes. So, you know, with the proof of stake, we have all
一旦您过渡到投票。因此，您知道，有了股份证明，我们有
of these validators that do attestations and stuff like this. So, basically, we want to
在这些有证明和这样的事物的验证者中。因此，基本上，我们想
stop, and we did stop using blocks as the way to kind of measure weight. So, you know,
停下来，我们确实停止使用块作为测量重量的方式。所以，你知道，
we were talking about heaviest, we think of weight.
我们在谈论最重的，我们想到体重。
But in this case, really weight is just whatever it is.
但是在这种情况下，真正的体重只是什么。
Well, it's actually difficulty.
好吧，这实际上是困难。
It's not like one block comes for one.
这并不是一个街区出现。
There's the difficulty part.
有困难部分。
But anyway, in Perlmere Stake, we really
但是无论如何，在Perlmere的股份中，我们真的
want weight to be basically given by boats and by stake,
希望重量基本上由船和危险赋予
essentially.
本质上。
And so we kind of do the same thing,
因此，我们也有同样的事情
except that now we have this kind of weighted block tree,
除了现在我们有了这种加权块树，
or like a block tree with boats, with these little clouds, which
或像船上的街区一样，有这些小云
are at the stations.
在车站。
And then, yeah, LMD Ghost is basically message-driven,
然后，是的，LMD Ghost基本上是消息驱动的，
so basically vote-driven ghost, but also latest.
因此，基本上是投票驱动的鬼魂，但也是最新的。
So we only consider the most recent vote
因此，我们只考虑最近的投票
for any given validator.
对于任何给定的验证器。
But other than that, it's the same thing essentially.
但是除此之外，本质上是同一件事。
So yeah, and we can also, so far,
是的，到目前为止，我们也可以
we've talked about LMD Ghost as a fourth-choice algorithm,
我们已经谈论了LMD Ghost作为第四个选择算法，
but you can also think about it as a protocol,
但是您也可以将其视为协议，
and actually it is basically what our protocol is.
实际上，这基本上就是我们的协议。
So you take, this is a slot of the protocol
所以您接受，这是协议的一个插槽
and basically it starts with a proposal
基本上它是从提案开始的
where a block is kind of added to the block tree.
块中添加了一个块。
Then there's these head boats where you just basically,
然后是这些头船，您基本上是
which kind of an attestation of today
今天哪种证明
or one part of our attestations
或我们证明的一部分
where basically each validator just says,
基本上每个验证者都说的地方，
this is what I think is the head of the chain
我认为这是链的头
and that's it, then another proposal
就是这样，然后是另一个建议
and it keeps going like this.
而且它一直像这样。
And basically this is what our slots look like,
基本上，这就是我们的老虎机的样子，
except that we also have attestation aggregation
除了我们也有证明汇总
that kind of complicates things.
这种事情使事情复杂化。
So we actually have three phases instead of two, but it's sort of irrelevant here.
因此，我们实际上有三个阶段，而不是两个阶段，但这在这里是无关紧要的。
So it basically looks like this block is proposed,
因此，基本上看起来像是提出了这个块，
people vote on it and move on and they kind of, you know,
人们对此投票并继续前进，他们有点
these people that put on it, they try to kind of give way to it
这些穿上它的人，他们试图让位
and make sure that it stays then in the chain to kind of impose their view of the chain.
并确保它停留在链条中，以强加他们对链条的看法。
So that's how it goes.
所以就是这样。
And then there is the customer for G part, which is this friendly
然后是g部分的客户，这是这种友好的
finality gadget or any finality gadget
最终的小工具或任何终结小工具
it, where basically it's okay, we start with some block tree, and then we consider some
在基本上可以的地方，我们从一些块树开始，然后我们考虑一些
of them, some of the block tree checkpoints, in our case, the echo boundary blocks, and
其中，某些块树检查点，在我们的情况下，回声边界块，
then we try to finalize some of these checkpoints so that basically we prevent reorgs, which
然后，我们尝试最终确定其中一些检查点，以便基本上可以防止重新
might happen with the protocol like it goes.
协议可能会发生。
And yeah, basically, we have this essentially links between checkpoints, which then lead
是的，基本上，我们在检查点之间实质上具有这种链接，然后领导
to first justification and then finality if you have to consec well if you have like a justified
如果您有合理的理由，则首先是理由，然后结局
block and then uh immediately another uh link starting from it um i'm not gonna go into details
块，然后立即从它开始的另一个uh链接，我不会详细介绍
with this but basically this you can think of it as just any kind of pbft style protocol any kind
有了这个，但基本上，您可以将其视为任何类型的PBFT样式协议
of you know quorum based protocols that really tries to have this like hard finality guarantees
您知道基于法定人数的协议确实试图拥有像坚硬的最终确保的协议
we just lay it on top of our um underlying kind of work choice like a lindy ghost and basically
我们只是将其放在UM的基础工作选择上，例如Lindy Ghost，基本上是
try to get the benefits of finality on top of whatever our underlying protocol is.
尝试在我们的基本协议中获得最终效果的好处。
And yeah, that's basically what Ethereum looks like today.
是的，这基本上就是以太坊今天的样子。
We have a bunch of slots, 32 of them form an epoch.
我们有一堆插槽，其中32个形成了一个时代。
And for each slot, we elect a committee, which is pseudo-randomly chosen from our validator
对于每个插槽，我们选举一个委员会，该委员会是从我们的验证者中选择的伪随机
set.
放。
And basically, each slot looks like LMD Ghost, more or less.
基本上，每个插槽看起来都像LMD幽灵，或多或少。
But then on the level of Epochs, we have a Caspar Fuji operating, trying to finalize stuff.
但是，在时代的水平上，我们有一个Caspar Fuji操作，试图最终确定内容。
So this is like kind of two layers that we have.
因此，这就像我们拥有的两层。
And yeah, basically at the layer of Epochs, it kind of looks like this.
是的，基本上是在时代的层面上，看起来像这样。
But in each slot, it looks like a Lambda ghost.
但是在每个插槽中，它看起来像是一个lambda鬼。
One way to think about it kind of formally is this model of an n-band flow protocol,
正式思考它的一种方法是这种N波段流程的模型，
protocol, where basically we think about it as having kind of operating in two modes.
协议，我们基本上将其视为在两种模式下操作。
Basically, we both worry about the network being partially synchronous, meaning we kind
基本上，我们俩都担心网络部分同步，这意味着我们很友善
of want to worry about periods of time where the network might not be synchronous, but
想担心网络可能不是同步的时间期间，而是
we also want to look at what happens once it does become synchronous.
我们还想看看一旦它变得同步会发生什么。
And so this is kind of the standard model for PBFT protocols.
因此，这是PBFT协议的标准模型。
And basically, the other thing that we care about that's sort of non-standard is that
基本上，我们关心的另一件事是非标准的
we want to look at what happens if participation is dynamic.
我们想看看如果参与是动态的，会发生什么。
So basically, if validators are coming and going, sometimes they go offline, maybe there's
因此，基本上，如果验证者来来去去，有时他们会离线，也许有
a major unpredictable event where half of the validators go offline, whereas in which
一半的验证者脱机，而其中的一个重大不可预测的活动
case, like a normal BFT protocol with finality, like Casper, basically by itself would stop
案例，就像普通的BFT协议一样，像Casper一样，基本上会停止
functioning, because you wouldn't be able to form these two-thirds forms.
功能，因为您将无法形成这三分之二的表格。
And yeah, so this part, you know, because we look at this participation model, we basically
是的，所以这部分，您知道，因为我们看这个参与模式，我们基本上是
want to have this property called dynamic availability, which is essentially that the
想要将此属性称为动态可用性，从本质上讲，
available chain, in our case, LMD ghost, this thing that kind of goes on by itself
在我们的情况下，可用的链条是LMD Ghost，这种事情本身还在继续
before we get to finality.
在我们达到最终状态之前。
We want it to be safe and live, like basically to work
我们希望它能安全和生活，就像基本上一样工作
as long as the network is synchronous.
只要网络是同步的。
And even if we have dynamic participation,
即使我们有动态参与，
kind of ignore exactly these things, it doesn't matter.
有点忽略这些事情，没关系。
And yeah, other than that, we want basically finality,
是的，除此之外，我们基本上想要结局，
which is like, we do want that, you know,
就像，我们确实想要那样，你知道
as long as the network becomes synchronous
只要网络变得同步
and we have high participation, we can finalize.
而且我们的参与很高，我们可以完成。
So the finalized chain is basically live.
因此，最终链基本上是活的。
And of course, the final chain will also be safe, but that's kind of by default almost.
当然，最终链也将是安全的，但这几乎是默认情况下。
So that's an easy part.
这很容易。
And then we have these two chains, the finalized chain and the non-finalized chain.
然后，我们拥有这两个链，即最终链和非预设链。
We don't want them to have nothing to do with each other.
我们不希望他们彼此无关。
We want them to have this prefix property where basically the finalized chain is like a prefix of the whole chain.
我们希望他们拥有此前缀属性，其中最终链基本上就像整个链的前缀。
So in our case, you know, the finalized block is always or like
因此，就我们而言，您知道，最终块总是或喜欢
if you look at the tip of the Ethereum chain,
如果您看以太坊链的尖端，
finalized blocks are always behind it somewhere.
最终确定的块总是在其后面。
They're not like randomly different blocks that have nothing to do with them.
它们不像与它们无关的随机不同块。
And yet to kind of the
尚未
to ensure this property of prefix,
为了确保前缀的此属性，
we basically have to somehow mesh together
我们基本上必须以某种方式融合在一起
the this to, you know, these two protocols like it goes and it comes pretty.
您知道这两个协议都像它一样，它变得很漂亮。
In our case, we do it with this hybrid fork choice, where basically, instead of saying
就我们而言，我们以这种混合叉选择来做到这一点，基本上不是说
just run LMD ghost, we say run LMD ghost from the latest justified checkpoint.
只需运行LMD Ghost，我们就会说从最新合理的检查点运行LMD Ghost。
Roughly, that's not exactly how it goes.
粗略地说，这并不是那样的发展。
There's some details, but yeah, at a high level, it's kind of the important thing.
有一些细节，但是，在很高的水平上，这是重要的事情。
So basically, here you can see there's some app box, some things are going on, some blocks
因此，基本上，在这里您可以看到一些应用程序框，有些事情正在进行，有些块
are being voted on.
正在投票。
The next app box, same thing.
下一个应用程序框，同一件事。
this block has been justified
这个块是合理的
and this block has been finalized
而且这个块已最终确​​定
like basically there's this super majority link
就像基本上有这个超级多数链接
which makes this block justified
这使这个块证明了
then another link from here to here
然后从这里到这里的另一个链接
which makes this finalized and this justified
这使得最终确定，这是合理的
so this is the level of Casper g
所以这是卡斯珀G的水平
and now this is the latest justified
现在这是最新的合理
it's like the you know the block of highest epoch
就像你知道最高时代的街区
which is justified
这是合理的
and we start our fork choice from that
我们从此开始我们的叉子选择
and then from here we run LMD goes
然后从这里运行LMD
So it is going to run it goes on this kind of circled block three
因此，它将运行它在这种圆圈的第三块
and yeah, then we get to be on this one being the head of the chain.
是的，那么我们就可以成为链的头。
So this kind of orange thing from here that that chain ends here,
因此，从这里到这里结束的这种橙色的东西，
whereas the blue chain is this one is like the, you know,
而蓝色的链条就像是，你知道，
the head of the finalized chain is this one, the latest finalized block.
最终链的负责人是最新的最终块。
And yeah, basically starting the fortress from the latest justified
是的，基本上是从最新有道理的堡垒开始
is enough to kind of ensure it is property
足以确保它是财产
because the latest justified is always a descendant of the latest finalized, so it sort of ensures
因为最新的理由始终是最新最终确定的后代，因此可以确保
that everything works out, unless there is like a, I mean, basically a huge slashing kind of thing.
一切都奏效了，除非我的意思是，除非有一个巨大的削减。
Yeah, one issue is that LMD Ghost, as it originally was implemented in Gaspar, has a bunch of problems,
是的，一个问题是，LMD Ghost最初是在Gaspar实施的，有很多问题，
and I'll kind of try to go through some of them and give you intuition for why the
我将尝试通过其中一些，并为您提供直觉
problems exist and what we can do about them, and what we have already done about some of them,
存在问题以及我们可以对它们做的事情，以及我们已经为其中一些做的事情，
So the most annoying problem that I guess existed originally, which really was a huge breaking issue until it was resolved, is this what's called an ex-ante reorg, which is a reorg attack which is set up by the adversary in advance.
因此，我猜最初存在的最烦人的问题是，这确实是一个巨大的打破问题，直到解决问题之前，这就是一个所谓的前任reorg，这是一个reorg攻击，这是由对手提前设定的。
Usually you think about reorgs as someone proposes a block, someone is participant,
通常，您会考虑某人提出的障碍，有人是参与者，
and then you somehow reorg it later.
然后，您以后再重新修复。
But here it's you somehow set up the reorg in advance.
但是在这里，您以某种方式提前设置了Reorg。
It's kind of similar to selfish mining in some sense.
从某种意义上说，这类似于自私采矿。
You withhold some things and then reveal them later.
您扣留一些东西，然后稍后透露它们。
So in this case, yeah, basically the adversary withholds this block and votes.
因此，在这种情况下，是的，基本上，对手拒绝了这一障碍和投票。
So the honest people, they vote for the previous block, because they just don't know about
因此，诚实的人，他们投票支持上一块，因为他们只是不知道
any of this stuff.
任何东西。
That's what it's meant by it not being fully the boundary.
这就是它的意思，因为它不是完全的边界。
And yeah, so then a Nautilus proposer builds a block on this one, because again, they don't
是的，那么一位nautilus提议者就在这一方面建立了一个街区，因为他们又不
know anything about this one.
对此一无所知。
Finally, the adversary reveals everything, and at this point, so this is after this block
最后，对手揭示了一切，此时，这是在这个障碍之后
has been built, but before it's stationed for it to come, so there's some time between
已经建造了，但是在驻扎之前，
these two things happening, and the adversary manages to reveal everything kind of right
这两件事发生了，对手设法揭示了一切正确的事
it at the right time so that this person, this proposer doesn't know that it should
它在正确的时间，以便这个人，这个提议者不知道应该
build on this one, but also every tester of this slot will know about this in time.
建立在这个基础上，但此插槽的每个测试仪都会及时知道这一点。
And so what they end up doing is they end up testing this one, and kind of forking out
因此，他们最终要做的就是他们最终测试了这一测试，然后分叉
this one, because they see that this block is there and has some weight.
这个，因为他们看到这个块在那里并且有一定的重量。
And then you continue, even if the next guy is honest, at this point, this one is already
然后您继续，即使下一个家伙是诚实的，此时，这个已经是
being worked out through no fault of its own.
通过没有自己的错来解决。
This was the state of things at the very beginning, I guess, three years ago.
我想三年前，这是一开始的状态。
Basically, when the beacon chain launched, this was an attack that existed.
基本上，当Beacon连锁店启动时，这是一项攻击。
You could do this.
你可以做到这一点。
For example, Barnabas did this on test nets.
例如，巴纳巴斯在测试网上做到了这一点。
It was kind of funny at the time, because you actually could have done this on main
当时有点有趣，因为您实际上本可以在Main上这样做
net, it's just that people didn't know about it.
网络，只是人们不知道。
The fix to this is what's known as Proposer Boost, which is basically kind of a way to
解决此问题是所谓的提议者的提升，这基本上是一种方法
go back to Ghost in some sense, it's kind of a hybrid between LMD Ghost and Ghost, where
从某种意义上说，回到鬼魂，这是LMD Ghost和Ghost之间的混合体
it basically gives some weight to a block just because it's being a block, even if it
基本上，它仅仅是因为它是一个块，即使它是一个块
doesn't have any votes.
没有任何选票。
So in Ghost, the attack before wouldn't have worked by itself, because once you've
因此，在幽灵中，以前的攻击不会单独起作用，因为一旦您
you propose a block, the block is its own weight.
您提出了一个块，块是其自身的重量。
Like, the block has a weight by itself.
就像，块本身具有重量。
So ProposerBoost is basically saying, OK,
因此，ProposerBoost基本上是在说，好的，
once you propose a block, at least temporarily
一旦提出一个块，至少暂时
for one slot, you're going to be given a little bit of weight
对于一个插槽，您将得到一点体重
that kind of allows you to protect yourself
这种使您能够保护自己
against this revealed attestations, potentially.
反对这一点，有可能证明。
So in our case, ProposerBoost is set to 40%
因此，在我们的情况下，PropoSerboost设置为40％
of one committee's weight.
一个委员会的体重。
And so if the adversary controls less than 40%,
因此，如果对手控制少于40％，
it basically wouldn't be able to do this attack,
基本上无法进行此攻击，
Because this red bubble will be less than 40%,
因为这个红色泡沫将小于40％，所以
and ProposerBoost will win, basically.
基本上，Proposerboost将获胜。
And this is just temporary weight.
这只是暂时的重量。
At the end of the slot it goes away.
在插槽结束时，它消失了。
But the nice thing is that once it goes away
但是好事是一旦它消失了
at the end of the slot, in the meantime,
在插槽结束时，与此同时
more attestations will have piled up on this block.
更多的证明将堆积在这个街区。
The attestations of this slot would have come,
这个插槽的证明会到来，
and so they should take care of things.
因此，他们应该照顾好事。
So that's true, but still not quite.
所以这是真的，但仍然不完全如此。
There's still some attacks that are possible, because if you do control some validators,
仍然有一些攻击，因为如果您确实控制了某些验证器，
even if it's not 40%, if you did control 40%, you could actually do this attack.
即使不是40％，如果您确实控制了40％，则实际上可以进行此攻击。
This should be 40%, and then you could actually do the same attack before and just beat Proposer
这应该是40％，然后您实际上可以进行相同的攻击，然后击败提议者
Boost.
促进。
The thing is, you can do it with less than 40%, because, for example, if you control
问题是，您可以以少于40％的速度进行操作，因为例如，如果您控制
two slots in a row, now you can withhold two blocks and two red bubbles.
连续两个插槽，现在您可以扣留两个块和两个红色气泡。
So these are different votes from different committees.
因此，这些是不同委员会的不同投票。
So for example, if this was 20%, you could do this attack again.
因此，例如，如果这是20％，则可以再次进行此攻击。
As soon as you control two slots in a row, you can do this attack.
一旦您连续控制两个插槽，就可以进行此攻击。
And that's you can do today.
那就是你今天可以做的。
Today, if you control 20%, you could try to do this.
今天，如果您控制20％，则可以尝试这样做。
And if you could control even more slots in a row,
如果您可以连续控制更多的插槽，
you need to control even less adversarial power to do this.
您需要控制更少的对手能力才能做到这一点。
Of course, at some point, if you have very little adversarial power,
当然，在某个时候，如果您的对抗力量很小，
the likelihood of you controlling a lot of blocks in a row is very small.
您连续控制许多块的可能性很小。
So that's why this is not a super breaking issue.
这就是为什么这不是超级突破问题的原因。
But of course it's not ideal that someone with 20%
但是当然，拥有20％的人并不理想
could go and do this reorg, or even 10%
可以去做这个reorg，甚至10％
if you have four slots in a row or something like that.
如果您连续有四个插槽或类似的插槽。
But yeah, but that is the state of things today.
但是，是的，但这就是今天的状态。
And so again, basically, that's what would happen
再一次，基本上，这就是发生的事情
if you did this.
如果您这样做。
You would basically overcome Proposer Boost
您基本上会克服提议者的提升
by doing the same revealing in time thing as before.
通过与以前的时间进行相同的揭示。
And now the honest attesters would attest to this one,
现在，诚实的证明者会证明这一点，
because they would see that the red bubbles are
因为他们会看到红色的气泡是
more than proposer boost, and then it would keep going like that, like this chain it will
不仅仅是提议者的提升
have won basically and forked out this one.
基本上赢了并分散了这一奖项。
Then yeah, let me skip this.
那是的，让我跳过。
I mean it's it's just another tactic it's kind of similar same principle it's just basically
我的意思是这只是另一种策略
you try it, I mean similar principle, not exactly same, but yeah you basically try to
您尝试一下，我的意思是类似的原则，不是完全相同，但是是的，您基本上尝试了
just set up a situation where the honest people flip-flop between two branches by it, like
只是设置了一个诚实的人在两个分支之间拖上触发的情况，就像
you keep the two branches kind of balanced,
您保持两个分支保持平衡，
and you use your own votes, like these red bubbles,
而且您使用自己的选票，例如这些红色泡沫，
to kind of flip back and forth.
来回翻转。
And this is also helped by Proposer Boost,
提议者Boost也有所帮助，
because at this point, you will have
因为在这一点上，您将有
these green votes being quite similar,
这些绿色投票非常相似，
this red bubble trying to break the tie one way or another.
这个红色的泡沫试图以一种或另一种方式打破领带。
But then Proposer Boost, as long as it's
但是随后提议者提升，只要是
more than these red bubbles, can take care of things
除了这些红色的气泡，还可以照顾好事
and make sure that whatever the Proposer happens to see
并确保任何提议者碰巧看到的一切
is actually what people are going to do.
实际上是人们要做的。
But again, this is vulnerable to,
但同样，这很容易受到攻击，
if you can control more bots than boosts, then that can be a problem.
如果您可以控制比Boost更多的机器人，那可能是一个问题。
So there's, like, these attacks exist, what do we do about them? And, I mean, of course,
因此，存在这些攻击，我们该怎么办？而且，我的意思是，当然
ideally you would want, you wouldn't want to just come up with some kind of patch, but you would
理想情况下，您想要的，您不想想出某种补丁，但是您会
want a protocol that is theoretically secure, in particular, like, an available chain, then there's
想要一个理论上安全的协议，尤其是一个可用的链条，然后有
the whole finality stuff, but, and I mean, that part, like, works in our protocol, but you would
整个终结性的内容，但是，我的意思是，那部分就像在我们的协议中起作用，但是您会
want basically to fix this available chain so that it's really theoretically secure, possibly
希望基本上要修复此可用链，以便在理论上确实安全，可能
like in an optimal way, so that you just can prove that it doesn't have any of these attacks.
就像以最佳方式一样，您可以证明它没有任何这些攻击。
And yeah, basically the first thing is trying to improve on Proposer Boost. So there's this idea
是的，基本上，第一件事是试图改善提议者的提升。所以有这个想法
it's called ViewMerge, which I think a bit more at this point is like kind of a tool to think
这就是所谓的ViewMerge，我认为此时更像是一种思考的工具
easily of better protocols in some way it's not necessarily something that you know we should
在某种程度上容易获得更好的协议，这不一定是您知道我们应该的东西
for sure put in the protocol at some point but I think it's helpful to use it as a way to think of
可以肯定在某个时候放入协议，但我认为将其用作考虑的方式很有帮助
what is possible kind of it's like an easy way to say to well if it doesn't work with this then
如果不适合这个，那可能是一种简单的说法。
it's probably not going to work basically so yeah basically the idea is to make the slot
基本上可能不会工作，所以基本上是要使插槽
or like introduce a new face in the slot where validators basically freeze their view meaning
或喜欢在插槽中引入一张新面孔，验证者基本上冻结了他们的观点的含义
they basically are going to buffer new attestations and come in after that point.
他们基本上要缓冲新的证明，并在此之后出现。
And then they only consider them when voting in the next slot if the proposer says so.
然后，如果提议者这样说，他们只有在下一个插槽中投票时考虑他们。
If the proposer tells them, hey, I know about this attestation.
如果提议者告诉他们，嘿，我知道这一证明。
If you have it in your buffer, please consider it.
如果您的缓冲区中有它，请考虑。
And the point of this is basically a lot of these attacks revolve on trying to sneak in attestations
这基本上是很多这些攻击试图偷偷摸摸的攻击
that the proposer doesn't see, but other people do.
提议者看不到，但其他人会这样做。
And here, basically, people give the proposer a bit of advantage.
在这里，基本上，人们给提议者带来了一些优势。
So, they freeze their view before the proposer does, so that anything that comes around the
因此，他们在提议者之前冻结了自己的观点，以便周围的任何东西
proposal deadline, people will have it in their buffer, not in their view, because
提案截止日期，人们将在缓冲区中，而不是他们认为，因为
basically, they would already have frozen their view in advance.
基本上，他们已经预先冻结了自己的观点。
And to try to make it a bit clearer, basically, let's say that I'm a validator at the view
并试图使它更清楚，基本上，假设我是视图的验证者
freezing time, so just before delta before the proposal, I have this view, which is just all
冻结时间，所以在提案之前的三角洲之前，我有这种观点，这只是全部
all the attestation votes that I know.
我知道的所有证明投票。
You keep gossiping things around,
你一直在闲聊，
so things that you receive,
所以你收到的东西，
hopefully the proposer also receives, like delta later.
希望建议者也会像Delta一样收到。
And so the proposer should know more than the attestor,
因此，提议者应该比认证者更了解
should have a bigger view than the attestors.
应该比证明人更有看法。
And now the proposer is gonna make a proposal
现在，提议者将提出建议
based on this view.
基于此观点。
So the view it's what informs it's work choice,
因此，这是信息选择的原因，
it's gonna tell it what the head of the chain is,
它会告诉它链的头是什么，
and it should inform where B is built on.
它应该告知B建立B的位置。
And then basically, the proposer also
然后基本上，提议者也
sends its view alongside b when it proposes b.
提出b时，将其视图与B一起发送。
So it just basically sends some kind
因此，它基本上发送了某种
of digest of which messages it might take into account
它可能考虑到哪些消息的摘要
when doing this.
这样做时。
And then this validator does this merge thing,
然后这个验证者完成了此合并，
which is it takes its frozen view
这是冻结的视图
and it merges it with the proposer view
并将其与提议者的观点合并
and obtains a new view.
并获得新的视图。
And now, because the proposer's view
而现在，因为提议者的观点
is a superset of its frozen view,
是其冷冻视图的超集，
it's just basically going to agree with the proposer.
这基本上是要同意提议者。
on what messages to consider. And so yeah, this basically solves, or improves this problem,
关于要考虑的消息。是的，这基本上可以解决或改善此问题，
because what we can now ensure is that no matter what the adversary does essentially,
因为我们现在可以确保的是，无论对手从本质上做什么，
no matter how powerful the adversary is, all the honest attesters, so here this green bubble,
不管对手有多强大，所有诚实的证明者，所以在这里这个绿色泡沫，
will attest to an honest proposal. So here there's some things going on, some balancing,
将证明一个诚实的建议。因此，这里有一些事情正在发生，有些平衡，
some sway votes, these red bubbles that are trying to confuse things, it doesn't matter
一些摇摆票，这些试图混淆事物的红色气泡，没关系
because all the honest attesters see the same block 3 as the proposer, YouTube view merge,
因为所有诚实的证明者都看到与建议者相同的块3，所以YouTube视图合并，
and so they all attest to it. And so all the honest votes, they do go where they're supposed
因此，他们都证明了这一点。因此，所有诚实的投票，他们都会去他们应该的地方
to go, which is to the honest proposal. And again, this is regardless of how powerful the adversary
去，这是诚实的建议。再说一次，这都是对手多么强大
is. But this is still not the whole story, even if we could implement this view merge thing,
是。但这仍然不是整个故事，即使我们可以实施此视图合并，
because x-hunter works are still possible if you control enough, yes, no matter how powerful the
因为X-Hunter的工作仍然是可能的，如果您能够控制足够
adversary is, these people will vote for this honest proposal. The issue is still afterwards,
对手是，这些人将投票赞成这个诚实的建议。此问题仍然是
the adversary can reveal more votes and go back to the other chain. So in this case,
对手可以揭示更多的选票，然后回到另一个连锁店。因此，在这种情况下，
like, you know, there's this green bubble here, but there's basically three red bubbles here. So
就像，您知道，这里有一个绿色的气泡，但是这里基本上有三个红色泡沫。所以
the adversary controls a few slots in a row, and depending on how much power it has, these,
对手可以连续控制几个插槽，并取决于它具有多少功率，这些，这些，
you know, three red bubbles might be more powerful than the green bubble. Like, if the adversary
您知道，三个红色气泡可能比绿色气泡更强大。像，如果对手
controls, I don't know, I guess 30% or something like that would be enough. Yeah, I don't know
我不知道控件，我想30％或类似的东西就足够了。是的，我不知道
about the exact number, but it's not hard to see how this could happen. So, basically,
关于确切的数字，但不难看到这可能发生的方式。因此，基本上，
exam-tree hooks are still possible. Now, the root cause of why they're still possible is that we
考试树钩仍然是可能的。现在，为什么仍然可能的根本原因是我们
have committees. So, if you remember this picture of, you know, we have RendOw, it's like we have
有委员会。因此，如果您还记得这张照片，您知道，我们有汇总，就像我们有
a validator set, then we split it up into committees randomly throughout an epoch.
一个验证者集，然后我们将其分为整个时期的委员会。
And this is the problem, because so LMD, this latest message thing, means that for each
这是问题所在，因为LMD，最新消息意味着每个信息
validator, we only counted most one vote. But across committees, I mean, in each committee
验证者，我们只计算了大多数投票。但是在整个委员会中，每个委员会中
there's different validators. So these votes and these votes are basically disjoint. It's
有不同的验证器。因此，这些投票和这些投票基本上是不一致的。它是
it's just different validators.
这只是不同的验证器。
So these votes kind of add up.
因此，这些投票加起来。
Like once you go between slots or across slots,
就像您在插槽之间或跨插槽之间一样，
weight can add up.
体重可以加起来。
And so these three red bubbles, they
所以这三个红色的气泡
do add up to basically three times as much weight as one.
总体加起来的重量是1的三倍。
And this is essentially what allows the adversary
这本质上是允许对手的原因
to save up and overpower the honest votes,
为了节省并压倒诚实的投票，
because the honest people in these cases
因为在这些情况下诚实的人
have only one bubble.
只有一个气泡。
And basically, yeah, the simple solution is do away with committees, just stop using committees.
基本上，是的，简单的解决方案是取消委员会，只是停止使用委员会。
But what does that mean? In practice, everyone should be voting every slot,
但是这是什么意思？实际上，每个人都应该投票
like every validator in Ethereum needs to be voting every slot so that there's no possibility
像以太坊中的每个验证者都需要投票，以便没有可能
of accumulating. This green bubble would mean all of the honest validators that exist in Ethereum,
积累。这种绿色泡沫意味着以太坊中存在的所有诚实验证者，
not just this one committee. Of course it's simple in quotes, because it's not actually simple,
不仅是这个委员会。当然，它的引号很简单，因为它实际上并不简单，
given how many validators we have, at least in theory, kind of.
鉴于我们至少在理论上有多少验证者。
But for now, let's just pretend that there's this VIP
但是现在，让我们假装有这个VIP
that's actually getting into Electra, which is MaxiB.
这实际上是进入伊莱克斯（Maxib）的伊莱克斯（Electra）。
And that's basically, you know,
基本上，你知道，
the idea there is to allow validators to consolidate their stake.
那里的想法是允许验证者巩固其股份。
So you can have a validator that has like 2,000 ETH of stake
因此，您可以拥有一个拥有2,000个股份的验证器
or something like that, and to actually contract a validator set.
或类似的东西，并实际收集验证器集。
So then maybe eventually we can get to having everyone vote at once,
因此，也许最终我们可以立即让所有人投票，
which is kind of the key thing here.
这是关键的事情。
And assuming that we have done that, somehow we have resolved this problem
并假设我们已经做到了，我们已经解决了这个问题
and done away with committees, can we finally have
并取消委员会，我们终于可以
approvably secure available chain?
可靠的可用链？
And it turns out that we can.
事实证明我们可以。
So there's this protocol that we've written a paper about some time ago
因此，有一段时间以前我们写了一篇论文
that's called our LMD ghost, and it's basically like a pretty simple
这就是我们的LMD幽灵，基本上就像一个非常简单的
modification of LMD ghost.
LMD幽灵的修改。
The first thing that it does is view merge.
它要做的第一件事是查看合并。
So we had this freeze period and this view merge thing.
因此，我们有这个冻结时期，这种观点合并了。
basically to replace ProposerBoost. And so again, what that does is,
基本上要替换PropoSerboost。再次，这是，
honest proposals are voted by all honest volunteers. And yeah, that's basically what
诚实的建议都由所有诚实的志愿者投票。是的，这基本上就是
it does, no matter what's happening here, all the green people go here. Then no committees,
不管这里发生了什么事，所有的绿色人都去这里。然后没有委员会
so we've somehow gotten rid of having committees and everyone votes at once. Of course,
因此，我们以某种方式摆脱了有委员会，每个人都立即投票。当然，
it's easier, but in practice it's not.
这很容易，但实际上不是。
And basically what this does is,
基本上，这是什么是
if all the honest validators agree on something
如果所有诚实的验证者都同意某事
in one slot, like they all vote for the same thing,
在一个插槽中，就像他们都投票给同一件事一样，
then this thing can never be re-org.
那么这个东西永远不可能被重新纠正。
So, you know, here, these people all vote
所以，你知道，在这里，这些人都投票
for the green thing before we had this, like,
对于绿色的东西，我们就这样，就像
re-org possibility where, like, we still go, you know,
重新说明我们仍然走的地方，你知道，你知道，
we still go up here because we have committees,
我们仍然去这里，因为我们有委员会，
but like once we get, yeah, the picture should change,
但是，就像我们得到的一样，是的，图片应该改变，
but I guess I didn't.
但是我想我没有。
But yeah, once we get rid of the committees,
但是，是的，一旦我们摆脱了委员会，
then as soon as everyone has voted here,
然后，一旦每个人都在这里投票，
then we'll never go away from this.
然后，我们将永远不会摆脱这一点。
Everyone's gonna keep building on this chain.
每个人都会继续建立这座链条。
And this is because this is really
这是因为这真的
at least half of the whole validator sets,
至少一半的整个验证器集，
like a majority of all of the validators.
就像大多数验证者一样。
So there's no way for the adversary to overpower that
因此，对手没有办法压倒这一点
because there's no way that they can accumulate votes.
因为他们无法积累选票。
Like basically these red bubbles,
就像基本上这些红色气泡一样，
they will also just be overlapping bubbles,
他们也将是重叠的气泡，
adversary can repeat the same votes but they only count once at the end of the day.
对手可以重复相同的选票，但一天结束时他们只计数一次。
And basically together, they kind of give us this property called reorg resilience,
基本上，他们为我们提供了这个称为Reorg弹性的财产，
which is that honest proposals are never reorgd. So honest proposals get voted by everyone,
这就是诚实的提议永远不会是重新的。因此，诚实的建议被每个人投票，
once something is voted by everyone, honest, then it never gets reorgd.
诚实，一旦所有人都投票了，那么它就永远不会得到重新核心。
And then, yeah, the other thing is this, maybe I'm going to skip this,
然后，是的，另一件事是，也许我要跳过这个，
I'm just gonna tell you briefly,
我只是要简短地告诉你，
like the R in our LMD go stands for board expiry,
就像我们的LMD GO中的R代表董事会到期一样，
which basically is that at some point
基本上是某个时候
you stop counting attestations that are too old.
您停止计算太老的证明。
So after some number of slots,
因此，经过一定数量的插槽，
you just stop counting their weight.
您只需停止计数他们的体重。
So for example, here, like these attestations,
因此，例如，在这里，就像这些证明一样，
they're too old and you just don't consider them anymore.
它们太老了，您只是不再考虑它们了。
And this is kind of it related to this concept
这与这个概念有关
of dynamic availability and basically being resilient
动态可用性，基本上是弹性的
cases where a bunch of people go offline, it means that we can always recover when a
一堆人离线的情况，这意味着我们总是可以在
large portion of the validators go offline.
验证者的大部分脱机。
Maybe just briefly, yes, basically, the scenario is this.
也许简短地，是的，基本上，情况就是这样。
Imagine that somehow all of the honest validators are split exactly in two, between two forks,
想象一下，某种程度上，所有诚实验证者都完全分为两分，两个叉子之间
but then basically these ones, they have gone offline, like half of the validator set is
但是基本上是这些，它们已经离线了，就像验证器集的一半是
offline um the chain continues here because there's like this little contribution from the red
离线um链条继续在这里，因为红色的贡献很小
ones that make uh you know basically this side have more weight so they keep voting uh and the
使您基本上知道这方面的人的体重更大，因此他们继续投票
latest boats are here but then the red boats uh come back to here uh okay so i'm always like
最新船在这里，但是红船呃回到这里
oh yeah okay uh yes then basically the red boats um shift back to the other chain and now we have
哦，是的，是的，基本上是红色的船，um返回另一个连锁店，现在我们有了
a reorg because basically the red boats are kind of the deciding boat here between the two chains
一个重复
because these green bubbles are the same and so here the red boats are kind of joining this
因为这些绿色气泡是相同的，所以在这里，红船加入了这个
coalition of like stale boats like this should be these are very old these people are offline
像这样的陈旧船的联盟应该是这些人离线很老
they're not voting anymore but their votes are still there um whereas and so yeah then
他们不再投票了，但是他们的投票仍然存在，而是，是的
everyone reorgs it here and we can have like a very long reorg um but yeah in with expiry this
每个人都在这里重新校园，我们可以像一个很长的reorg um一样，但是是的
this wouldn't happen, because eventually, these votes
这不会发生，因为最终，这些投票
just expire.
只是过期。
And so that kind of caps how long this reorder can be.
因此，这种重新订购的时间可以限制多长时间。
Once these have expired, then the adversary
一旦到期，对手
can't really do anything.
真的什么都不做。
These votes are all of the ones that
这些投票都是
matter at this point, basically.
基本上，这一点很重要。
And now, OK, we have basically the ingredients
现在，好吧，我们基本上有成分
to have a single softline-autoprotocol.
具有单一的软单元 - 小概括。
Basically, now, with all these things,
基本上，现在，所有这些事情，
we've already kind of constructed it in the paper.
我们已经在论文中构建了它。
But here, it just gives you the idea.
但是在这里，它只是为您提供了这个主意。
But we've already constructed a basically secure available chain in the kind of model that we care about.
但是，我们已经在我们关心的模型中构建了一个基本的可用链。
And basically, now we want to take this and make it into a single-stop finality protocol.
基本上，现在我们想将其纳入单板最终协议。
So basically put together, put on top of it, again, Casper 5G or some finality gadget,
因此，基本上将其放在一起，再次放在上面，再次是Casper 5G或一些最终的小工具，
and kind of get back something that looks like what we have today, but finalizes in a single slot,
并恢复了我们今天所拥有的东西，但在一个插槽中最终确定了
and is actually provably secure.
实际上是安全的。
So it doesn't have all these weird kind of attacks and edge cases.
因此，它没有所有这些奇怪的攻击和边缘案例。
So the rough idea, yeah, actually let's skip this.
因此，大概的想法，实际上让我们跳过这个。
Yeah, basically the idea of trying to make such a protocol
是的，基本上试图制定这样的协议的想法
is to, or like one kind of simple way to make sure
是或喜欢一种简单的方法来确保
that things work, which is basically how,
事情起作用，这基本上就是
like I think all the protocols that are known to work
就像我认为所有已知的协议一样
in this model are built, is that basically you only try
在此模型中是建立的，是基本上您只尝试
finalize blocks which are already confirmed by the underlying available protocol so in our case
最终确定的块已经由基础可用协议确认，因此在我们的情况下
lmd ghost so confirmed here means like the underlying available protocol has already kind
LMD Ghost在这里得到确认，这意味着像潜在的协议已经很友善
of attained a certain level of security for a block you can think of this as like k deep in
您可以认为这是一定程度的安全性，您可以将其视为深处
longest chain like a block that is like buried deep in the longest chain you don't think that
最长的连锁店就像一个块一样，就像埋在最长的链中，你不认为那是
that's kind of reorg like just a bitcoin kind of you know uh confirmation rule and you only try to
就像比特币一样，您知道确认规则，您只想尝试
finalize those things, like the ones that are confirmed, like buried deep or some other way
最终确定这些东西，例如被确认的东西，例如埋葬的深度或其他方式
of determining that it's this thing shouldn't be reorged. And this is like to make basically
确定这是不应重新改造的。这就像基本上做
the interactions between these two protocols, because we are kind of taking a protocol and
这两个协议之间的相互作用，因为我们是一种协议，并且
like putting one on top and all these kind of interactions, it makes them much nicer,
就像将一个互动和所有这些互动放在上面一样，它使它们变得更好，
because basically as long as things are working, like as long as this confirmation rule of the
因为基本上只要事情正在起作用，就像只要这种确认规则
underlying protocol is working, this finality gadget does not interfere with it. Like basically
基础协议正在起作用，此最终性小工具不会干扰它。基本上
it can only finalize things that are already never going to be reorged.
它只能最终确定已经将永远不会被重新改造的内容。
And we just have to worry about, okay, what if something breaks
我们只需要担心，好的，如果某事破裂怎么办
in the underlying protocol?
在基础协议中？
Like maybe there's some period of asynchronous, some attack,
也许有一段时间的异步，有些攻击，
and something in the underlying protocol that breaks.
以及基础协议中断断续续的东西。
Then, okay, we're going to try to recover from this,
然后，好吧，我们将尝试从中恢复过来，
but then there might be weird interactions.
但是，可能会有奇怪的互动。
And, okay, we have to make sure that these are handled,
而且，好的，我们必须确保处理这些处理，
which is not super easy, but doable.
这不是超级容易的，但是可行。
So, because of this, one thing that kind of was missing in the picture before is that
因此，因此，以前图片中缺少的一件事是
we didn't really have a confirmation rule, or, like, we did, I didn't explicitly say it, but
我们真的没有确认规则，或者像我们这样做的那样，我没有明确说出来，但是
it wasn't a fast confirmation rule. It was just basically it was something similar to kdip again,
这不是一个快速的确认规则。基本上，这再次与KDIP相似，
like the sort of, like, longest chain. And, yeah, basically, we want a fast one,
就像那种最长的链一样。而且，是的，基本上，我们想要一个快速的
because we want to finalize fast. And we can only finalize after confirming. The pipeline is, like,
因为我们想快速最终确定。确认后，我们只能最终确定。管道就像
propose a block, confirm it, finalize it, or justify it, finalize it. So, if you want single
提出一个块，确认，确定它或证明其合理性，最终确定它。所以，如果你想单身
slot finality, we should be confirming it in a single slot. So, we basically add another phase
插槽最终性，我们应该在一个插槽中确认它。因此，我们基本上添加了另一个阶段
to our slot for fast confirmation. What we do is basically say if a block is received at two-thirds
到我们的插槽以进行快速确认。我们要做的基本上说，如果收到三分之二的块
quorum from the whole validator set, because remember now two-thirds of the whole validator
整个验证器集中的Quorum，因为现在请记住整个验证器的三分之二
that are gonna be voting in every slot,
每个插槽都会投票，
then you confirm it in this phase.
然后，您在此阶段确认它。
And yeah, basically the key thing is that
是的，基本上关键是
once you confirm here, there's a bit more time,
一旦您在这里确认，还有更多时间，
like another sub-slot before freezing your view,
像另一个子插槽之前，在冻结您的视图之前，
like before you stop considering new things.
就像您停止考虑新事物之前一样。
And so if someone honest confirms here,
因此，如果有人诚实在这里确认
they then send this form here
然后他们在这里发送此表格
and everyone will take it into account
每个人都会考虑到它
in their frozen view.
在他们的冻结视野中。
So yeah, basically, again, this is the same picture as before.
是的，基本上，这是与以前相同的图片。
We are like, this is the view merge part.
我们就像，这是视图合并部分。
But somehow, we get to here.
但是不知何故，我们到达这里。
And everyone votes.
每个人都投票。
So this validator is going to send this attestation
因此，此验证者将发送此证明
for block B. A bunch of other people are doing the same thing.
对于B块B。其他许多人也在做同样的事情。
They're all voting for B. Like, for example,
他们都投票支持B。
if this is an honest slot, then this view merge pipeline works.
如果这是一个诚实的插槽，则此视图合并管道有效。
And everyone votes for B. And it quorum forms.
每个人都投票支持B和IT法定人数。
So now, we're at fast confirmation time.
所以现在，我们正在快速确认。
Every validator, honest validator,
每个验证者，诚实验证者，
is going to see this quorum for b.
要为b看到这个法定人数。
And then they send it over.
然后他们将其发送到。
And by the time that people are freezing
到人们冻结的时候
their view in the next slot, these frozen views,
他们在下一个插槽中的观点，这些冰冻的景色，
they all contain this quorum.
他们都包含这个法定人数。
And basically, this is what enables the confirmation rule
基本上，这就是实现确认规则的原因
to work, to actually be able to say,
工作，实际上可以说，
if anyone confirms, anyone honest,
如果有人确认，有人诚实，
then this block is not going to be reordered.
那么此块将不会被重新排序。
It's actually confirmed in a meaningful sense,
它实际上是有意义地确认的，
basically safety for the confirmation rule.
基本上是确认规则的安全性。
And yeah, basically we do have such guarantees
是的，基本上我们确实有这样的保证
as long as we have network synchrony,
只要我们具有网络同步，
which is always necessary for, you know,
您知道这总是必要的
unless you finalize and an honest majority.
除非您确定和诚实多数。
And same thing, we need an honest majority
同样的事情，我们需要诚实的多数
unless once you finalize then it's fine,
除非一旦您确定了，那就很好，
you have stronger guarantees.
您有更强的保证。
So the idea is basically, again,
因此，这个想法基本上是
if an honest validator fast confirms B,
如果诚实的验证器快速确认b，
then everyone else,
然后其他人，
every honest validator sees the quorum
每个诚实的验证者都会看到法定人数
before freezing its view.
在冻结视线之前。
And what this gives us is basically,
这基本上是
so let's look at basically what the picture would
因此，让我们从基本上看一下图片
look like then.
看起来像。
OK, let's say that this B is the thing that's
好，假设这个B是
being fast confirmed.
快速确认。
So everyone sees this greater than 2 thirds votes for B.
因此，每个人都看到B。
And then possibly some people that are in this quorum,
然后可能有些在这个法定人数中的人，
because this quorum might not be all honest people,
因为这个法定人可能不是全诚实的人，
it might also be malicious people,
可能也是恶意的人
they might have equivocated it.
他们可能已经将其等效到了。
So they might have voted for something else as well.
因此，他们可能也投票赞成其他事情。
In which case, the way it works in our protocol
在这种情况下，它在我们的协议中的工作方式
is that you basically take away that weight.
是您基本上会拿走那个重量。
Like if you know that a vote is in a prevocation,
就像您知道投票处于爆发状态一样，
you just don't count it's weight.
您只是不算它的体重。
So in this case, you know,
因此，在这种情况下，您知道，
this thing would have at least two thirds minus E,
这东西至少要有三分之二的负E。
like the prevocations.
喜欢前期。
Any other contender, like this could be,
任何其他竞争者都可能是
it could be a bunch of them, but anyway, you know,
可能是其中的一堆，但是无论如何，你知道，
at this point we're evaluating this block
此时，我们正在评估这个块
and all the weight on it against any other sub-three,
以及所有其他以下的重量，
basically any other like sibling that's competing with it.
基本上，任何其他与之竞争的兄弟姐妹。
And no matter what it's gonna need,
无论它需要什么，
it's gonna have less than one third.
它将不到三分之一。
it's basically the remaining votes are less than 1 third.
基本上，剩余的选票小于三分之一。
And then equivocations wouldn't matter
然后模棱两可就没关系
because you don't count them anyway.
因为您无论如何都不算​​它们。
And so as long as E is less than 1 third, then we're good.
因此，只要e小于三分之一，我们就很好。
Like then the leftover non-equivocating votes here
像那时，剩下的不备票的投票
are going to beat any other contender.
将击败任何其他竞争者。
And so basically, that means that everyone
因此，基本上，这意味着每个人
that sees such a thing is going to, in its frozen view,
从冰冻的角度来看，这样的事情将会变成
see that B is supported by enough votes to win,
看到B有足够的选票支持，以获胜，
basically, to be canonical.
基本上是规范。
And so in the next slot it's going to vote for it.
因此，在下一个插槽中，它将投票支持它。
And then, as we already kind of talked about before,
然后，正如我们之前已经谈论过的那样，
if everyone in the next slot votes on B, or the sub-3 of B,
如果下一个插槽中的每个人都对B或B的第3台投票
it could be that there's a proposal here,
可能是这里有一个建议，
and then everyone votes for that proposal.
然后每个人都投票赞成该提议。
But anyway, it's for the sub-3 of B,
但是无论如何，这是针对B的低于3的
then it's never going to get re-ordered, basically,
然后，它永远不会重新订购
as long as it's an anonymous majority.
只要这是匿名的多数。
Like, if these are more than half the whole valid data set,
例如，如果这些是整个有效数据集的一半以上，
they all vote for B, then it's fine, basically.
他们都投票支持B，然后很好，基本上。
So that's why the fast confirmation sort of works.
这就是为什么快速确认的原因。
I don't know why this slide is here.
我不知道为什么这张幻灯片在这里。
But yeah, oh yes, sorry, yeah, basically this was our LMD ghost, the structure of our LMD ghost.
但是，是的，哦，是的，对不起，基本上，这是我们的LMD幽灵，这是我们LMD幽灵的结构。
Then we've added fast confirmation.
然后，我们添加了快速的确认。
And then now we add some things that are kind of specific to Casper 5G to actually turn this into a finalizing protocol.
然后，现在我们添加了一些特定于Casper 5G的内容，以将其实际转变为最终确定协议。
So that's kind of the last step.
这是最后一步。
So here we just have head boats.
所以在这里我们只有头船。
So, you know, today attestations contain a head boat, which just says, you know, what you think is the head of the chain.
因此，您知道，今天的证明包含一艘头船，这只是说，您知道，您认为是链的头。
but then they also contain a Casper FFG vote.
但是随后他们还包含Casper FFG投票。
Here you just have a head vote.
在这里，您只是进行投票。
So same as our LMD ghost,
和我们的LMD鬼一样
where there's no finality.
没有最终的地方。
Then here instead, we have fast confirmation
然后在这里，我们有快速的确认
and then an FFG vote.
然后进行FFG投票。
So first head vote, then a FFG vote.
因此，首次投票，然后进行FFG投票。
Then we freeze our view for view merge to work.
然后，我们将视图冻结以使视图合并以工作。
And then there's this acknowledgement,
然后是这个确认，
which is basically another type of vote.
这基本上是另一种投票。
And so what it looks like at the end of the day
所以一天结束时的样子
is basically,
基本上，
So let's go through this first.
因此，让我们首先进行此操作。
Yeah, so the fork choice is, again, same as before,
是的，所以叉子的选择与以前相同，
this hybrid fork choice.
这个混合叉的选择。
Before, you start from the latest justified,
之前，您从最新的合理开始，
then you run rlmd-ghost.
然后，您运行RLMD-GHOST。
FFG votes are defined in this way, similar to today.
FFG的投票是通过这种方式定义的，类似于今天。
The latest justified is the source of the vote.
最新的理由是投票的来源。
And then the target block, so you
然后是目标块，所以你
want to add this link that it goes from latest justified,
想要添加此链接，该链接来自最新合理的
which is the thing you're trying to finalize, potentially,
这是您试图最终确定的东西
to some target.
到一些目标。
And again, basically, the target is something
同样，基本上，目标是
that is potentially going to become justified,
这有可能成为合理的理由，
it's the thing that you're trying to justify.
这是您试图证明合理的事情。
And so you want this to be confirmed so that if anything
因此，您希望对此进行确认，以便如果有的话
gets into this justification finalization pipeline
进入此理由确定管道
it starts affecting the fourth choice.
它开始影响第四个选择。
So here we start from the latest justified.
因此，我们从最新的合理开始。
So we want to make sure that the latest justified is something
因此，我们要确保最新的合理是
strong that already has strong security guarantees.
强大的安全保证。
And so you start from the highest confirmed block,
因此，您从确认的块开始，
Like basically the best block that you know that is confirmed.
就像基本上是您所知道的最好的块一样。
Okay, the highest confirmed block descending from justified
好的，确认最高的块从合理的
because it kind of fits with this forced choice rule.
因为这与此强制选择规则相吻合。
And yeah, and basically then acknowledgement is just you saying,
是的，基本上，确认只是您说的，
oh, if something is justified here, I know about it.
哦，如果这里有合理的理由，我知道。
Like if something is justified, you just acknowledge that you know about that.
就像是合理的，您只是承认您对此有所了解。
And it's essentially the same as if in the next slot
这与下一个插槽中的基本相同
you were to make an FFG vote that
您要进行FFG投票
has this block as the source.
将此块作为源。
This is a bit confusing if you haven't thought too much
如果您没有考虑太多，这有点令人困惑
about Casper-FFG, but you can think about it as basically
关于Casper-ffg，但您可以基本上考虑
this is just two rounds of voting,
这只是两轮投票，
the usual two rounds of voting that you
通常的两轮投票
need to finalize in PPFT, in Casper-FFG,
需要在ppft，casper-ffg中最终确定，
in all these protocols.
在所有这些协议中。
So this is just a second round of voting, basically.
因此，这基本上只是第二轮投票。
So basically what the pipeline looks like it's like, OK,
因此，基本上管道的样子，好的，
block is proposed, it's gossiped, people vote on it as a head vote, so they say, oh, this is my head
提出了街区，闲聊，人们对此进行投票，所以他们说，哦，这是我的头
of the chain, then people basically, you know, maybe a quorum forms, at which point here it gets
链条，然后人们基本上是一个法定人物形式，这是在这里得到的
confirmed, like people see a quorum, they confirm it, and if they confirm it, they can cast an FFG
确认，就像人们看到法定人数一样，他们确认了，如果他们确认，他们可以施放FFG
vote with it as the target, which is basically trying to justify it. Now, if a bunch of people
将其作为目标投票，这基本上试图证明它是合理的。现在，如果一群人
do this, a quorum forms of FFG votes, it gets justified, like by here, everyone knows that it
做到这一点，是FFG投票的法定形式，它是合理的，就像在这里一样，每个人都知道
it is justified, they all acknowledge it.
这是合理的，他们都承认这一点。
They all freeze their view with knowledge
他们都用知识冻结了自己的观点
of it being justified.
它是合理的。
And they send this new vote, and it gets finalized.
他们发送了新的投票，并将其最终确定。
So by the end of the slot, we've gone through all the kind
因此，到插槽结束时，我们已经经历了所有的
of phases, like confirmation, justification, finalization,
阶段，例如确认，理由，最终确定，
that are necessary.
那是必要的。
And yeah, so that's single-slot finality, basically.
是的，这基本上是单槽的最终结局。
And yeah, in an honest slot, it would really
是的，在一个诚实的位置上，这真的会
look exactly like this.
看起来完全像这样。
We cannot guarantee that this is what
我们不能保证这就是什么
it's gonna look like for every slot,
每个插槽都会看起来像
but for honest slots under synchrony and so on,
但是对于同步等诚实的老虎机，
then it is gonna look like this.
然后看起来像这样。
Basically, an honest proposer is gonna make
基本上，一个诚实的建议者会做
a timely Brok proposal B,
及时的惯例提案B，
and we can guarantee through V merge
我们可以保证通过V合并
that everyone casts a head vote for B,
每个人都对B进行了票数的投票
and it's gonna form a quorum.
它将形成法定人数。
Then everyone sees this quorum,
然后每个人都看到这个法规，
everyone confirms, fast confirms,
大家确认，快速确认，
and uses basically bt, like t being the slot.
并基本上使用BT，例如T是插槽。
So it's checkpoints are like a block and the slot,
因此，检查点就像一个块和插槽，
or like, I mean, in our current protocol,
或者，我的意思是，在我们当前的协议中，
but here, epochs and slots are the same thing,
但是在这里，时代和老虎机是同一件事，
because of single-cell finality.
由于单细胞的终结性。
And yeah, so basically, you cast this link, which
是的，基本上，您施放了此链接，
like you send a vote, which is basically for the link,
就像您发送投票一样，基本上是链接的投票，
latest justified to bt.
最新有道理的BT。
And everyone has the same latest justified again
每个人都有同样的最新合理
because of view merge.
因为视图合并。
The proposer can help everyone to see the same latest
提议者可以帮助每个人看到相同的最新
justified.
有理由。
So again, a quorum of these forms.
再次，这些形式的法定人数。
And so everyone sees now that bt is justified.
因此，现在每个人都看到BT是合理的。
And they basically acknowledge this fact,
他们基本上承认这个事实，
and then that leads to finality.
然后这导致了最终状态。
And then by this time, everyone should
然后到这个时候，每个人都应该
have seen that b is finalized.
已经看到B最终确定。
This is just a little aside.
这只是一边。
If you're interested in these things,
如果您对这些事情感兴趣，
Something that was sort of recently, kind of a recent development here was that, basically,
最近的某种情况，这里的一个最近的发展是，基本上是
we wanted to have a chain protocol.
我们想拥有一个链条协议。
So, you know, this protocol, everything happens in one slot, which is nice.
因此，您知道，这个协议，一切都在一个插槽中发生，这很好。
Like, you finalize it in one slot.
就像，您在一个插槽中最终确定它。
But it also kind of means, I mean, it means that we have three rounds of voting in a slot,
但这也是我的意思是，这意味着我们有三轮投票，
which is a lot, especially, you know, there's aggregation with the station.
尤其是，您知道，电台有聚集。
There's a lot of overhead involved in voting with a big validator set.
与大验证器组合投票的投票涉及很多高架。
But something that's nice that instead we would want to have is to have a chain protocol where you just vote once in every slot.
但是，我们想要拥有的是一个很好的事情，就是拥有一个链条协议，您只需在每个插槽中投票一次即可。
That's basically what we have today, right?
这基本上就是我们今天拥有的，对吗？
Like, today you just attest, you propose and attest in every slot.
就像，今天您刚刚证明，您在每个插槽中提出并证明。
And, okay, aggregation, but, like, you only vote once.
而且，好的，聚集，但是，您只投票一次。
And even Casper 5G itself, if you think about it on the level of epochs, it's chained.
甚至Casper 5G本身，如果您在时代的水平上考虑它，它也是束缚的。
Because in one epoch you're at the same time trying to justify something and finalize the
因为在一个时期内，您同时试图证明某事并确定
previous thing.
上一件事。
So you kind of do two phases at once.
因此，您同时进行两个阶段。
You don't wait for, for example, Tendermint is not a chain protocol, if you know what
例如，如果您知道什么，您不会等待，例如
Tendermint is.
Tendermint是。
Tendermint basically does one quorum, the other quorum, finalizes the thing, and then
Tendermint基本上做一个法定人，另一个法定人数最终确定了事物，然后
moves on.
继续前进。
So it's pretty fast for Fuji, basically, at the same time, we'll be trying to finalize
因此，对于富士来说，这是相当快的，基本上，我们将尝试最终确定
the thing that was already justified and to justify something new.
已经证明并证明新事物合理的事情。
So it sort of tries to move ahead of one step essentially, or to do two steps at once.
因此，它试图从本质上转向一个步骤，或者一次执行两个步骤。
And so we want to kind of do the same thing here.
因此，我们想在这里做同样的事情。
And yeah, basically it turns out that there's some complications in making it work, but
是的，基本上，事实证明它可以使它起作用，但是
it turns out that it seems like with some modifications it can work.
事实证明，似乎有一些修改可以起作用。
I'm not going to go into detail about what it looks like,
我不会详细介绍它的外观，
but basically, at the end of the day, at a high level,
但基本上，归根结底，高水平
it looks like it's this.
看起来就是这样。
Basically, we have three slots here.
基本上，我们在这里有三个插槽。
So this is the slot.
所以这是插槽。
And basically, the pipeline is essentially
基本上，管道本质上是
that you propose something.
你提出了什么。
Again, this is for honest proposals.
同样，这是出于诚实的建议。
It would work out like this.
它会这样奏效。
Everyone votes for it, for group B, and B gets confirmed.
每个人都为B组投票，B被确认。
So again, within one slot, we still
因此，在一个插槽中，我们仍然
this fast confirmation thing, basically the only difference is that we only have a single round of
这种快速确认的事情，基本上唯一的区别是我们只有一轮
voting. Basically this is today, you attest, you send a head vote and an FFG vote bundled together,
表决。基本上，这是今天，您证明，您发送了一笔投票，FFG投票捆绑在一起，
which do both things at once, actually three things at once. They do head vote for the head
同时完成这两种事情，实际上是三件事。他们确实为头投票
of the chain, FFG vote, and the FFG vote does two things at once, because again CasperFG is
链条，FFG投票和FFG投票立即做两件事，因为Casperfg再次是
pipelined, so the target of the FFG vote is trying to justify something, and the source of the FFG
管道上，因此FFG投票的目标正在试图证明某些事情是合理的，而FFG的来源
vote is trying to finalize something so you're like at once really doing three votes like one
投票正试图最终确定某些内容，因此您就像一次真正地进行三票一样
to confirm one to justify it one to finalize um and so yeah basically b would be confirmed
要确认一个可以证明一个符合嗯的合理性，所以是的，基本上B将被确认
once you get here uh everyone would know b is confirmed they would be using bt as their
一旦您到达这里，每个人都会知道B被确认他们将使用BT作为他们的
target so this is the thing that you're trying to justify and then get into the next slot you would
目标是这样，这是您试图证明合理的事情，然后进入下一个插槽
be using uh bt as your source so now you're trying to finalize it basically and so it goes through
将UH BT用作您的来源，因此现在您正在尝试基本上最终确定它，因此它可以通过
confirming, justify, and finalizing within three slots. And it's nicer in some ways.
在三个插槽内确认，合理和最终确定。从某种意义上说，这是更好的。
And it takes some complications. Someone who is writing Roberto from ConsenSys has been working
这需要一些并发症。从共识中写罗伯托的人一直在工作
on a spec for this, because we felt like this might be a good version of the protocol to actually
在这个规格上，因为我们觉得这可能是该协议的好版本
try to write it down a bit more nicely. And so yeah, this is actually something
尝试将其写下来。是的，这实际上是
that there's ongoing work on it. Maybe you can potentially get involved if you're, I don't know,
正在进行的工作。如果您不知道，也许您可​​能会参与其中，
masochist and you like these things um and yeah so that's kind of it for the more um
受虐狂，你喜欢这些东西，是的
i guess more like ssf related things and it's just generally the board like technical things in
我猜更像是SSF相关的事物，通常只是董事会就像技术一样
in the uh in the fourth choice and i kind of just wanted to uh use some of the remaining time to
在第四个选择中的UH中，我只是想使用剩下的时间来
give an overview of some of the other things as well that uh where the fourth choice fits in the
概述了其他一些选择适合的其他事项
ethereum roadmap because it turns out that it like pops up in a bunch of places where you actually
以太坊路线图，因为事实证明它像在您真正的许多地方弹出
he wouldn't want it to pop up, but unfortunately it does.
他不希望它弹出，但不幸的是它确实如此。
So before we move on, can we have a second for some questions?
因此，在我们继续前进之前，我们可以有一秒钟的问题吗？
Yeah, yeah, sure.
是的，当然。
Sorry, yes, yes, yes.
抱歉，是的，是的。
Yeah, it's all right.
是的，没关系。
So it's a lot to digest.
所以要消化很多。
So there was a question regarding, yeah,
所以有一个问题，是的，
so if you can elaborate, what's the BLS signature
因此，如果您可以详细说明，什么是BLS签名
count limit or slot in SSF scenario?
在SSF方案中计数限制或插槽？
On whether it is a limit?
关于这是否是限制？
What's the limit on count of BLS signatures in Slot?
插槽中BLS签名计数的限制是什么？
I mean, so nowadays, we aggregate, I guess,
我的意思是，如今，我们想，我们汇集了
like around 3,000 votes per Slot,
就像每个插槽大约3,000票一样，
because there's about a million validators,
因为大约有100万个验证者
and like 30-ish thousand are in every committee,
像每个委员会中的30万一样，
or in a committee.
或在委员会中。
So we had, like, with George, proposed this two-layer
因此，我们和乔治一起提出了这个两层
aggregation where basically you do what we do today,
聚集基本上您今天要做的事情，
but for a bunch of committees in parallel.
但是对于一群并行的委员会。
And then you kind of aggregate those
然后你有点汇总
and try to get basically more committees participating
并尝试使更多的委员会参与
at once essentially.
本质上是一次。
And it turns out it seemed like, yeah, that's fine in some way,
事实证明，看起来，是的，这在某种程度上很好，
but it does run into some kind of limits with basically
但这确实遇到了某种限制
the main part is the verification
主要部分是验证
the final huge PLS thing that you get at the end, in the worst case you have to do this really
最后，您最终得到的最终巨大的事情是，在最坏的情况下，您必须这样做
large edition of pubkeys, and that seemed to be the limiting thing, and partially also the
大型Pubkeys，这似乎是有限的，也部分是
networking of it all, but I think more of this verification bottleneck. So it was something like,
这一切的网络，但我认为更多的验证瓶颈。所以这就是
oh, if you had to do this for, I think, a million validators, Georgia some benchmarks for,
哦，如果您必须这样做，我认为是一百万验证者，佐治亚州的一些基准，
before, then on some, you know, on Raspberry Pi it might take, like, 36 seconds or something.
然后，在某些情况下，您知道，在Raspberry Pi上可能需要36秒或其他东西。
And it's very parallelizable, but it's still on better machines it would take maybe, I
而且它非常可行，但是它仍然在更好的机器上，也许我
don't know, like a second, two seconds, depending on how parallel it is, it was kind of borderline
不知道，就像一秒钟，两秒钟，具体取决于它的平行程度，它是一种边界
impractical, I would say.
我要说的是不切实际的。
completely out of the realm of things that you could possibly do, but still not quite
完全摆脱了您可能要做的事情的范围，但仍然不是很
something that you probably want to do today.
您今天可能想做的事情。
So, yeah, I hope that sort of answered your questions.
所以，是的，我希望那种回答您的问题。
Thank you so much.
太感谢了。
So another question was regarding the slide 35 all the way back in, I don't know how to
所以另一个问题是关于幻灯片35，我不知道该怎么
see the numbers.
看到数字。
Oh, okay, I can see it.
哦，好吧，我可以看到。
yeah yeah so regarding the view merge uh what happens if proposer is this honest uh if the
是的，是的，关于视图的合并，如果提议者是诚实的，如果是
proposer is what it is honest nothing really it basically the the nice thing about it is that
提议者是诚实的，什么都没有
they cannot prevent so maybe let's go here um you know if someone honest votes their vote will get
他们无法阻止，所以也许让我们去这里，嗯，如果有人诚实投票，他们的投票就会得到
to everyone before they freeze so all of the honest votes will be in the frozen views i mean
在所有人冻结之前，所有诚实的投票都将在冷冻的观点中，我的意思是
assuming network is synchrony. So the proposer can't really do that much. It cannot somehow
假设网络是同步的。因此，提议者实际上不能做太多。它不能以某种方式
censor honest votes, because they don't depend on the proposer to end up in the final merge view.
审查诚实的投票，因为他们不依赖提议者最终成为最终合并观点。
The only thing that the proposer can do is basically to confuse people about late votes.
提案者唯一能做的就是基本上是让人们混淆较晚的选票。
If there's some votes that only show up here or here or something like that, then the proposer
如果有一些只有在这里或这里出现的选票或类似的票，则建议者
can send maybe some merge message to some people or to some other people and confuse things,
可能会向某些人或其他人发送一些合并信息，并使事情混淆，
but that's what you already can do as a dishonest proposer like uh uh you know all this like
但这就是您已经可以像不诚实的建议者那样做的
withholding and like publishing late blog late messages and that's stuff that you can already
预扣和喜欢发布博客后期消息，这是您已经可以的东西
do so it actually does not give you any more adversarial power which it sort of formalized
这样做实际上不会给您更多的对抗力量，它是正式的
by the fact that we've actually proved that this protocol is secure so it turns out like yeah the
实际上，我们实际上证明了该协议是安全的，因此事实证明是像
The adversary can't really do anything with that.
对手实际上无法做任何事情。
Okay, awesome.
好吧，很棒。
I think we can go ahead and move to the roadmap powerpoint
我认为我们可以继续前进到路线图PowerPoint
and then we'll leave more questions.
然后，我们将留下更多问题。
Okay.
好的。
Okay, yeah.
好吧，是的。
Yeah, so kind of, I guess what we talked about so far
是的，好吧，我想我们到目前为止所说的话
is a single-cell finality, just to recap our fast finality.
是一个单细胞的最终性，只是为了回顾我们的快速终结。
What is good about it is basically
它的好处基本上是
that it's, first of all, optimally secure,
首先，它是最佳安全的，
like provably optimally secure.
就像证明是最佳安全的一样。
Or we can hopefully get a protocol
否则我们可以获得协议
like the ones I've described, even in practice.
就像我所描述的那样，即使在实践中也是如此。
These are more like papers at this point and the beginning
这些更像是论文和开始
of a spec, but still, there's proofs,
规格，但仍然有证据，
and they get optimal security guarantees,
他们获得了最佳的安全保证，
so ideally what you like, basically.
因此，理想情况下，您基本上喜欢什么。
And so that's one thing, like not having to chase patches and fixes of this attack and that attack,
因此，这是一回事，就像不必追逐贴片和这种攻击和攻击的修复，
and then another attack comes up and all this stuff. Then the other thing is that we have
然后发生了另一次攻击，所有这些东西。那另一件事是我们有
basically, you know, just obviously, like, that's why you, you know, you want fast finalities,
基本上，您知道，很明显，就像，这就是为什么您知道，您想要快速的最终决定，
like, you can immediately have really good guarantees, like if you're transacting a lot
就像，您可以立即获得很好的保证，例如交易很多
of money, once finality happens, you're pretty sure that it's not going to be reverted. For
金钱，一旦发生结局，您很确定它不会被恢复。为了
for example, exchanges can do deposit fast,
例如，交易所可以快速存款，
you get better bridging, basically for the same reasons,
您会得到更好的桥接，基本上是出于相同的原因，
and you get better L2 interoperability,
而且您可以获得更好的L2互操作性，
and also that's kind of the same reason
这也是同样的原因
as better bridging, basically.
基本上是更好的桥接。
Quickly, an L2, once some transaction's finalized,
很快，一旦某些交易完成，L2，
maybe there's a proof for it,
也许有证据
if you have fast validity proofs,
如果您有快速的有效性证明，
then another L2 can already talk to you,
然后另一个L2可以与您交谈，
do asynchronous calls and things like that quickly.
迅速进行异步电话和类似的事情。
Then, yeah, the other two items where it shows up,
然后，是的，它显示的其他两个项目，
it shows up in a bunch of places,
它出现在许多地方，
but two things that maybe people are familiar with is EPDS,
但是也许人们熟悉的两件事是EPD，
and then another one is DATAS, Data Availability Sampling.
然后另一个是数据，数据可用性采样。
So first, before getting into some of these things,
因此，首先，在进行其中一些事情之前，
let's talk about some kind of for-choice variant
让我们谈谈某种选择的变体
that turns out to be quite useful for a bunch
事实证明这对于一堆很有用
of these things.
这些东西。
And yeah, this is called block slot for-choice.
是的，这称为“块插槽”。
The idea is basically to allow people
这个想法基本上是为了允许人们
to vote against blocks.
投票反对障碍。
So far, you can just vote for blocks.
到目前为止，您可以只投票支持块。
You can't really say, oh, I don't
你不能说，哦，我不
want this block to become canonical.
希望这个区块成为规范。
And here, you sort of can.
在这里，您有点可以。
Or you can think about it as voting for an empty slot.
或者，您可以将其视为投票支持一个空的插槽。
So basically, the status quo is maybe you have block A,
因此，基本上，现状可能是您有块A，
block B is proposed.
提出了B块。
But imagine that block B is late.
但是想象一下B块很晚。
Today, a decision deadline is four seconds.
今天，决定截止日期为四秒钟。
Maybe it comes at 5, or it comes at 3.9 or something.
也许是5，或者3.9之类的东西。
Only a few people see it.
只有少数人看到了。
And these people attest to it, but most people
这些人证明了这一点，但大多数人
attest to A, the parent of B.
证明A，B的父母。
And so today, sure, that happens, but then still,
因此，今天当然，这会发生，但是仍然
like B has some weight.
像B有一些重量。
This weight is to the parent of B,
这个重量是给B的父母
so it still contributes to B. And in theory,
因此，它仍然有助于B。从理论上讲，
there's a caveat that proposer boost is also used for reorgs,
有一个警告，建议提示者也用于reorgs，
but let's leave that aside.
但是，让我们把它搁置一旁。
Basically, B would still be the head of the chain at this point.
基本上，在这一点上，B仍然是链的头。
Instead, we block slot, basically what would happen
相反，我们阻止了插槽，基本上会发生
is that instead of having this block three,
是的，而不是拥有这个块三，而是
we have a block slot three.
我们有一个块插槽三。
So instead of A, we have A at slot T.
因此，我们在插槽T中有一个。
And then there would be an A at slot T plus 1.
然后将有一个a处的a处t plus 1。
And I'm putting in blue the ones that are past their slot.
我把那些已经超越了他们的插槽的蓝色。
So here, basically, this is saying this slot is empty.
因此，在这里，基本上是说这个插槽是空的。
It's saying, oh, A existed at slot T.
这是说，哦，插槽T。
And then, well, nothing was timely extending A at this slot.
然后，没有什么可以及时扩展到这个插槽了。
So we put this placeholder A t plus 1, saying,
因此，我们将这个占位符的t plus 1放在
the way you should extend A at slot t plus 1 is with nothing,
您应该在插槽t plus 1处伸展的方式一无所有，
with an empty slot.
带一个空插槽。
So in this case, it would be the same.
因此，在这种情况下，它将是相同的。
A few people vote for B t plus 1, a non-empty block
一些人投票支持b t plus 1，一个非空的块
or non-empty block slot.
或非空块插槽。
But a lot of people vote for this empty one.
但是很多人投票赞成这个空的人。
And actually, the empty one would win,
实际上，空的人会赢，
basically putting this in the block 3
基本上将其放在块3中
so that these votes don't go to the parent,
这样这些投票就不会交给父母
but it go to this, it means that actually this empty thing
但这是这样，这意味着实际上是这个空虚的东西
can beat this one.
可以击败这个。
And so if this isn't timely, it's going to get reordered.
因此，如果这不是及时的，它将被重新排序。
It's just never going to become canonical.
它永远不会成为规范。
People basically vote on the empty block or slot,
人们基本上对空块或插槽进行投票，
and they basically prevent this thing from becoming canonical.
它们基本上阻止了这件事成为规范。
Kind of bigger example, maybe this one is timely,
一个更大的例子，也许这个是及时的，
so this does exist, but it doesn't get any votes.
因此，确实存在，但是没有任何选票。
Everyone votes for this one.
每个人都对此投票。
Then maybe this slot is empty, and everyone, like, just here,
然后，也许这个插槽是空的，每个人都喜欢在这里，
maybe the proposer just doesn't show up.
也许提议者并没有出现。
There's no contender.
没有竞争者。
Everyone votes for this slot to be empty.
每个人都投票赞成这个插槽为空。
There's also this one, but no one votes for it.
还有这个，但没有人投票。
Again, there's also this one, but no one votes for it.
同样，还有这个，但没有人对此投票。
But finally, in the last slot, we
但最后，在最后一个插槽中，我们
have this kind of case of this block being, sorry,
对不起，有这样的情况，
this new block being late.
这个新块迟到了。
So no one votes for it, because it's late.
因此，没有人投票赞成，因为它很晚。
everyone votes for yet another empty B slot,
每个人都投票支持另一个空的B插槽，
so in this case, B, T plus 3.
因此，在这种情况下，b，t plus 3。
And then this becomes canonical.
然后这变成了规范。
So now we have two blocks, two empty blocks
所以现在我们有两个街区，两个空块
kind of extending the chain.
有点扩展链。
And this is the canonical chain, culminating in this empty block.
这是规范链，最终在这个空块中。
And yeah, basically, this is what it would it look like
是的，基本上，这就是它的样子
with today's fourth choice.
有今天的第四个选择。
Like A comes, B comes, everything is fine.
就像来了一样，B来了，一切都很好。
You're a missed slot, people vote for B.
您是一个错过的插槽，人们投票给B。
And now C is late, people vote for B again.
现在C迟到了，人们再次投票支持B。
So all this empty stuff just disappears,
所以所有这些空的东西都消失了，
and B stays the head of the chain.
B保持链的头。
Sorry, sorry, I mean, well, B is in the chain,
对不起，对不起，我的意思是，b在链中，
but C actually is the head of the chain,
但是C实际上是链的头，
because there's nothing going against it.
因为没有任何反对。
There's no empty block.
没有空块。
Once you run your fork choice, you go A, B,
一旦您选择了叉子，就可以了A，B，
and then there's only one child, so you end up at C. Whereas
然后只有一个孩子，所以你到了。
here, you end up still at B.
在这里，您最终仍在B.
Some applications of this are useful are, one is this pretty generic idea of committee enforceable
它的某些应用很有用，一个是委员会可执行的一个非常通用的想法
properties, which is that basically if a certain proposed block does not fulfill a certain property,
属性，这基本上是，如果某个提议的块不符合某个属性，
the attesting committee or the attesters will vote for the empty block, so they'll vote against it,
证明委员会或证明者将投票支持空块，因此他们将投票反对，
it, basically to say, we don't want this block to become canonical.
基本上可以说，我们不希望这个区块成为规范。
So for example, inclusion list satisfaction, that's not what the current proposal is, but
因此，例如，包含列表的满意度，这不是当前建议，而是
there was like, one of the original proposals used this mechanism.
有一个原始建议之一使用了这种机制。
So where it basically, the enforcement of the inclusion list was based on basically
因此，基本上，加入列表的执行基本上是基于
a committee looking and saying, does this block satisfy the inclusion list that I know
一个委员会的看法，这个障碍是否满足我知道的包含清单
about?
关于？
Yes.
是的。
Okay, great, I'll go for it.
好吧，太好了，我去做。
No, then I'm going to vote for the empty block.
不，那我将投票给空块。
it and trying to make sure it does not become canonical because it didn't satisfy this thing
它并试图确保它不会变成规范，因为它无法满足这件事
it was supposed to satisfy.
它应该满足。
Similar thing is with map burn, which is basically, there's some bids and you try to make sure
类似的事情是刻录地图，这基本上有一些投标，您会尝试确保
that the block proposal maximizes, it chooses a bid that is maximal, the highest that you've
该块提案最大化，它选择了最大的出价，您是您的最高
seen by some time, and otherwise you vote against it.
看到一段时间，否则您会投票反对。
The other two things again is EPBS and DAS.
另外两件事是EPB和DAS。
So in EPBS, basically,
因此，在EPB中，基本上
proposers will accept bids from builders.
提议者将接受建筑商的竞标。
And basically, if they,
基本上，如果他们
like one thing that a proposer can do
就像建议者可以做的一件事
is try to grief a builder by accepting the bid but late,
试图通过接受竞标但迟到来悲伤建造者，
just publishing a block which accept this bid late.
只需发布一个较晚的竞标的街区即可。
And the builder then kind of is put in an awkward situation
然后，建造者会陷入尴尬的境地
where it doesn't know quite what to do.
它不知道该怎么办。
And so it blocks a lot, it enforces timeliness,
因此，它会阻碍很多，它执行及时性，
it makes sure that if you don't publish it early enough,
它可以确保如果您不够提早发布，
like by that decision deadline,
像该决定截止日期一样，
then you don't get attestations for your block,
那你就没有得到证明，
and then it's not gonna win,
然后它不会赢，
like it's gonna be basically orphaned.
就像它基本上是孤儿一样。
And so it kind of gives some safety to this mechanism.
因此，这可以使这种机制有些安全。
And yes, for choice, the idea here is that
是的，选择，这里的想法是
if a block is unavailable,
如果一个块不可用，
so I mean, we can set up things in such a way
所以我的意思是，我们可以以这样的方式设置东西
that through sampling, that most honest validators,
通过抽样，最诚实的验证者，
even if none of them is downloading all of the data,
即使他们都没有下载所有数据，
their sampling, but most of them will see
他们的抽样，但他们中的大多数会看到
that the block is not available.
该块不可用。
There may be like a small percentage of them that doesn't,
其中可能没有一小部分，没有，
but most of them will vote against it
但是他们中的大多数会投票反对
basically for the empty block.
基本上是空块。
And so because of block slot,
因此，由于块插槽，
unavailable blocks will just not be able
无法获得的块将无法
to become canonical, or even to look canonical,
成为规范，甚至看起来很典型，
meaning like, you know, if you somehow don't know
含义，例如，如果您以某种方式不知道
that they're unavailable, you still
他们不可用，你还是
wouldn't think that they're canonical.
不会以为它们是规范的。
Even if, for some reason, your sampling has failed,
即使出于某种原因，您的抽样失败了，
you've been tricked into maybe a small percentage of the data
您可能被欺骗了一小部分数据
is available, and that's exactly the data that you've requested.
可用，这正是您要求的数据。
Someone's targeting you in this data release attack.
在此数据发布攻击中，有人针对您。
But you still wouldn't think that the block is canonical
但是您仍然不会认为该块是规范的
just because you wouldn't get enough weight.
仅仅因为您不会得到足够的体重。
So basically, honest majority would
因此，基本上，诚实的多数会
protect the whole mechanism, which is nice.
保护整个机制，这很好。
it also just means that as long as there's an honest majority it basically doesn't mess up
这也意味着，只要有诚实的多数，基本上就不会弄乱
with consensus, this whole availability thing, I'll kind of explain it a bit later better. One
有了共识，这是整个可用性的事情，我将稍后再解释。一
problem with block slots, like one challenge, is that if you do have higher latency, again as I
块插槽的问题（例如一个挑战）是，如果您确实具有更高的延迟，那么我又是我
said it enforces timeliness, but sometimes blocks being late is just someone trying to do something
说这会执行及时性，但有时封锁迟到只是一个试图做某事的人
weird, some attack or timing games or something, but sometimes higher latency just happens,
很奇怪，一些攻击或定时游戏之类的东西，但有时会发生更高的延迟，
And then, you know, if that were the case,
然后，您知道，如果是这样，
the blocks don't make it into four seconds,
这些块不将其分为四秒钟，
they wouldn't get attested.
他们不会被证明。
Everyone would attest to the empty block.
每个人都会证明空块。
Block production would halt.
块生产将停止。
So, you know, you would get the situation where,
因此，您知道，您将得到情况，
okay, this block was late.
好吧，这个街区迟到了。
People attested to the empty block.
人们证明了空地。
Then this one forks it out because this one wins.
然后，这是因为这个获胜，因为它赢了。
Or, sorry, yeah, this C should extend this one.
或者，对不起，是的，这个c应该扩展这一点。
And this should extend this one.
这应该扩展这一点。
But anyway, yeah, they extend the empty blocks
但是无论如何，是的，他们延长了空块
coming before them.
来到他们面前。
But yeah, anyway, the point is that
但是，无论如何，重点是
none of these blocks is ever timely.
这些障碍都没有及时。
it never gets it stations, it keeps growing, it doesn't do anything it just you do have
它永远不会得到它的电台，它不断增长，它没有做任何事情
basically still state transitions in the beacon chain, but it will not actually have any content,
基本上仍在信标链中陈述过渡，但实际上不会有任何内容，
like neither beacon nor execution content.
像信标和执行内容一样。
So, but still, that's a challenge, and I guess I should say about this, so one important
所以，但这仍然是一个挑战，我想我应该对此说，所以一个重要的
thing in trying to do this, if we need it, to do block slot,
尝试这样做的事情，如果需要的话，可以做块插槽，
is to basically design some kind of back-off system, which
基本上是设计某种后退系统，
makes it so that if such a situation happens,
这样做，如果发生这种情况，
we somehow gracefully, maybe failed gracefully,
我们以某种方式优雅地，也许优雅地失败了，
like try to revert to maybe turn it off in some way,
就像尝试恢复以某种方式将其关闭一样，
like revert to actually producing blocks,
就像恢复为实际生产块一样，
even if it maybe damages some things that block slot was
即使这可能会损害某些障碍插槽的事情
helping.
帮助。
And so yeah, this is actually sort of an open question.
所以，是的，这实际上是一个悬而未决的问题。
I mean, I have some ideas on how this can work.
我的意思是，我对这可以如何工作有一些想法。
But I think if people are interested in this general space
但是我认为，如果人们对这个一般空间感兴趣
of problems, I think this is something where literally
问题，我认为这是从字面上看的
anyone could come in and spend some time and write up
任何人都可以进来花一些时间写信
a decent back-off protocol.
一个不错的退缩协议。
So that would be quite helpful, I think.
我认为这将很有帮助。
And yeah, so let's kind of look at just
是的，所以让我们来看看
how things fit into APBS, because that's also
事物如何适应APB，因为这也是
pretty open space of, you know, there's some problems and solutions are many and confusing,
您知道，很开放的空间，有很多问题和解决方案很多，而且令人困惑，
and so there's definitely work to do there.
因此，肯定有工作要做。
I think you guys had some, Barnaby gave a talk, so I'm assuming you're familiar with
我想你们有一些，巴纳比说话，所以我假设你熟悉
E-PBS or just a general E-PBS idea, so I don't think I have time to say too much about it,
E-PB或仅是E-PBS的一般想法，所以我认为我没有时间对此说太多，
But basically, there's just this part of the block production
但基本上，只是块生产的这一部分
process, which is bidding and accepting bids.
流程，即竞标和接受投标。
So here, a proposer is going to accept
所以在这里，提议者将接受
this bidP, which in this case is like a header execution header.
这个BIDP，在这种情况下就像标题执行标头一样。
And then the builder will reveal the actual execution payload
然后建造者将揭示实际执行有效载荷
P, like the full thing.
P，就像完整的事情一样。
So this is just a commitment to it.
因此，这只是对此的承诺。
And so one of the things that was proposed for in protocol
因此，协议中提出的一件事之一
PBS or in Shrine PBS is this two-slot approach,
PBS或Shrine PBS是这种两槽方法，
where basically the commitment part,
从基本上是承诺部分的地方，
the accepting the actual BeaconProposer accepting
接受实际的BeaConproposer接受
the payload header, it happens in its own slot.
有效载荷标头，它发生在自己的插槽中。
And then the reveal of the payload happens in its own slot.
然后，有效载荷的揭示发生在自己的插槽中。
And this kind of, it makes things nice, like in some sense,
这样，它使事情变得不错，就像在某种意义上
like it's easy to think about the security
就像很容易考虑安全性
of the participants involved.
参与者的参与者。
Like everyone kind of acts as a proposer,
像每个人一样，作为提议者的行为
gets it's own attestations.
得到自己的证明。
And you can basically think of it as like,
您基本上可以将其视为
As long as in the protocol today,
只要在当今的协议中，
proposers have some kind of good guarantees,
建议者有某种良好的保证，
like they can use ProposerBoost
就像他们可以使用PropoSerboost
to defend themselves against attacks decently enough,
为了捍卫自己的攻击，足够的攻击，
then both builders and proposers in this protocol
然后在此协议中都在
should have decent guarantees.
应该有体面的保证。
Now, the problem is that we are again faced
现在，问题是我们再次面对
with exantery orgs, but like in an EPPS kind of annoying,
与Epps有些烦人一样，有一种令人讨厌的人
more powerful version, where basically,
更强大的版本，基本上
so exantery orgs, again, remember it's something like this,
因此，Exantery Orgs再次记住，这是这样的，
where you withhold blocks and votes,
您扣留块和投票的地方，
and then you reveal them to try to reorg,
然后，您透露他们尝试重新
in this case, to like beat, propose, or boost,
在这种情况下，喜欢跳动，提出或提升，
and create a reorg.
并创建一个reorg。
And it's really relies on this, like,
它确实依赖于此，就像
accumulation of voting power.
积累投票权。
Now, the EPS version of this is just same thing,
现在，这是同一件事的EPS版本，
but now, these, like, two, you know,
但是现在，这些，就像两个，你知道，
before they had to be two actual slots, two actual blocks,
在必须是两个实际插槽之前，两个实际块
here it's gonna be, like, this kind of, you know,
在这里，它会像这样，你知道，
beacon slot, an execution slot.
信标插槽，执行插槽。
And the thing about it is that it basically means
关于它的事情基本上意味着
the adversarial power is doubled.
对抗力量增加了一倍。
Like, as soon as I control one slot,
就像，一旦我控制一个插槽，
I also can control the next one.
我也可以控制下一个。
I can choose myself as the builder,
我可以选择自己作为建造者，
or I can collude with a builder, or something like that.
或者我可以与建筑商或类似的东西串通。
And so now I control two slots and two red committees,
因此，现在我控制了两个插槽和两个红色委员会，
basically.
基本上。
And so I can immediately have as much power as two,
因此，我可以立即拥有与两个一样多的力量，
if I control two proposers.
如果我控制两个建议者。
And if I control two of them, now I have as much power as four
如果我控制了其中两个，那么现在我拥有四个的力量
and this kind of thing.
还有这种事情。
So that's the rough idea of why it basically
所以这就是为什么它基本上是一个大概的想法
makes all of these attacks quite worse.
使所有这些攻击变得更糟。
So that's not ideal.
所以这不是理想的。
And yeah, there's another proposed version,
是的，还有另一个建议的版本
which is actually one slot, where you introduce
实际上是一个插槽，您介绍
this other kind of committee that's
另一个委员会
called Payload Timeliness Committee, which is still
称为有效载荷及时委员会，这仍然是
voting, but it's really voting on a yes or no question of just
投票，但实际上是对只是或否的质疑
was the payload that was committed here timely?
在这里犯下的有效载荷是否及时？
Was it not timely?
不是及时吗？
And yeah, I don't want to go too much in detail,
是的，我不想详细地走得太多
but there are also some questions here of,
但是这里也有一些问题，
This is some problem with basically the protocol not
这是一些问题，基本上是协议
giving super great guarantees to builders.
为建筑商提供超级保证。
Like, they can be basically forced
就像，基本上可以强迫
to reveal a payload without being sure that,
在不确定的情况下揭示有效载荷，
or having a strong guarantee that it's
或有很大的保证是
going to become canonical.
要成为规范。
And yeah, there's some proposals on maybe how to fix that,
是的，有一些关于如何解决的建议，
but things are not entirely clear.
但是事情并不完全清楚。
Potus is the person to talk to if you're interested in this
如果您对此感兴趣，POTUS是与之交谈的人
and he's worked on this more.
而且他对此进行了更多工作。
I haven't more recently.
我最近还没有。
But anyway, so this is one of the things that has kind of
但是无论如何，这是具有某种的事情之一
blocked partially EPPS plus the fact that I mean there's other questions around you know whether
封锁了部分epps加上我的意思是，您周围还有其他问题知道是否知道是否知道
or not we actually want to do it or which versions or things like that but there's like basically no
还是不是我们实际上想这样做，或者是哪些版本或类似的事情，但基本上没有
matter what version of it you can propose that I've ever heard there is always some of these
无论您可以提出什么版本
fortress problems involved with them like pretty much all this the same kind of space of problems
堡垒的问题与他们一样几乎所有同样的问题空间
And so, yeah, basically, no matter what, I think this is something that will need to be dealt with,
因此，是的，基本上，无论如何，我认为这是需要处理的东西，
essentially. So, the nice thing is that in our LMD ghost, so going back to our kind of nice,
本质上。因此，好事是在我们的LMD幽灵中，所以回到我们的好处，
theoretically functioning protocol where everyone votes at once, there's no committees and stuff
理论上运作的协议，每个人都一次投票，没有委员会等
like that. So, if you remember, we didn't have xm3 orgs in our LMD ghost, and the reason for that is
这样。因此，如果您记得的话，我们的LMD幽灵没有XM3 orgs，原因是
we don't have committees. So it's basically the same thing here. Before I use this for expiry,
我们没有委员会。因此，这里基本上是同一件事。在我将其用于到期之前，
but here it's just that these are not the latest messages anymore. These are the latest messages,
但是这里只是这些不再是最新消息。这些是最新消息，
these are the latest messages. So there's no accumulation again. The same thing that
这些是最新消息。因此，再也没有积累了。同样的事情
we had before. These votes represent honest votes from basically a majority of the validator set,
我们以前有过。这些投票代表了基本上大多数验证者集合的诚实投票，
and they cannot be beaten by it by these ones there's because this is not a committee this
而且它们不能被这些人殴打，因为这不是一个委员会
is really like half of the validator set or more than half the validator set and so it fixes the
实际上就像验证器集的一半或验证器集的一半以上，因此修复了
problem in the same way as before basically the same guarantee that as soon as an honest guy shows
问题与以前相同的方式与基本相同的保证
up everyone votes for it and that's enough like then it doesn't matter what happened in the past
每个人都投票赞成它，就像过去发生了什么一样
basically so it kind of it it fixes like the the the root problem of xanthory orgs even if you
基本上，它是一种像黄金组织的根问题一样修复的，即使您
you put it into this EPPS context.
您将其放在EPPS上下文中。
So yeah, same thing, and then you keep going with it.
是的，同样的事情，然后您继续前进。
Everyone's going to keep building on that chain.
每个人都将继续建立在那条链上。
And now pretty much the last thing,
现在几乎是最后一件事
basically the fourth choice affects the peer DAS
基本上，第四个选择会影响同伴DAS
part of the roadmap, or just generally the DAS part
路线图的一部分，或通常只是DAS部分
of the roadmap.
路线图。
So it just very quickly kind of giving you
所以它很快就给了你
the idea of what's the availability sampling,
关于可用性采样的想法，
in case you don't know, but it's a few slides.
如果您不知道，但这是一些幻灯片。
Basically, we have blobs today,
基本上，我们今天有斑点，
that would be this blue part of data
那就是数据的蓝色部分
that roll up supposed to Ethereum.
那应该滚到以太坊。
Now, the idea of DAS is that we want to extend them.
现在，DAS的想法是我们要扩展它们。
So we want to basically apply it as a ratio coding thing
因此，我们希望基本将其应用于比率编码的东西
where you double their size,
您的大小加倍的地方，
and so you add this orange part and introduce redundancy.
因此，您添加此橙色部分并引入冗余。
And now, as soon as you have half of all of these cells
而现在，一旦您拥有所有这些细胞的一半
or data points, then you can reconstruct the whole thing.
或数据点，然后您可以重建整个过程。
And so checking that a blob is available
因此检查是否有斑点
means just checking that 50% of it is available.
意味着只检查其中的50％可用。
And so you can basically do this kind of sampling thing
因此，您基本上可以做这种抽样的事情
of just checking a few spots randomly chosen.
仅检查一些随机选择的斑点。
And basically, as long as a lot of people are doing this,
基本上，只要很多人这样做，
you know that, like, you really don't need
你知道，你真的不需要
to check the whole thing to kind of convince yourself
检查整个事情以说服自己
that it's available, or at least like,
它可用，或者至少喜欢
in most of a small amount of people that are doing it
在大多数这样做的人中
can be fooled into thinking that it's something
可以愚弄以为这是什么
that is unavailable is available.
这是不可用的。
And yeah, basically once you look at a bunch of blobs,
是的，基本上，一旦您看一堆斑点，
it looks pretty much the same way,
看起来几乎相同，
at least in the current proposal.
至少在当前的提案中。
There's 1D versus 2D, but the current thinking
有一维对2D，但是当前的思维
is to start with 1D.
是从1D开始。
And so basically you just stack blobs on top of each other.
因此，基本上，您只是将斑点堆放在彼此之上。
Each one is extended like this.
每个人都这样扩展。
And then you basically download columns.
然后您基本下载列。
So it's the same as here.
所以它与这里相同。
you just choose some indices, but then it's
您只选择一些索引，但是
as if you just choose the same indices for every blob.
好像您只是为每个斑点选择相同的索引。
And so you do sampling on every blob in the same spots.
因此，您可以在同一斑点中的每个斑点上进行采样。
And so that's the same as just downloading a bunch of columns
因此，这与仅下载一堆专栏一样
from this matrix.
从这个矩阵。
And then, yeah, basically, if half of the columns
然后，是的，基本上，如果一半的列
are available, then the whole thing is available.
可用，然后全部可用。
And so if you download a few columns,
因此，如果您下载了几列，
you can have the same guarantees.
您可以拥有相同的保证。
Now, the nice thing about doing this from a forechoice
现在，从预言中这样做的好处
perspective is that as long as you can do enough sampling it doesn't have to be like all of the
观点是，只要您可以做足够的取样，就不必像所有
sampling maybe you want to do more later um saying this because there's different ways to do sampling
抽样也许您以后要做更多的事情，因为有不同的方法可以进行抽样
and there's some ways they're more expensive um and but anyway it doesn't super much matter but
而且有些方法更昂贵，但是无论如何，这并不重要，但是
basically as long as you can do enough download enough columns before you vote like at any point
基本上，只要您可以在任何时候投票之前进行足够的下载列
you ever vote for something you really do sampling before that uh we can get this really good global
您曾经投票给您真正进行抽样的事情，嗯，我们可以得到这个非常好的全球
property, which is that it mostly really, the small percentage of honest validators
财产，这实际上是诚实验证者的一小部分
can basically, well, yeah, this should say, like, can ever vote for unavailable data. So,
基本上可以，是的，这应该说，这可以投票给无法使用的数据。所以，
oh yeah, okay, no, that's what it says later. Yeah, it's okay. And most, a small percentage
哦，是的，好的，不，这就是稍后所说的。是的，没关系。大多数，很少
of the honest validators can see unavailable data is available. So, that's just because of
诚实的验证者可以看到无法可用的数据。所以，那只是因为
doing sampling, and particularly if you do it before voting, then by voting time,
进行抽样，特别是如果您在投票之前进行采样，然后通过投票时间，
then you have this property. So because of that, if you have at least 1.5 plus delta,
然后，您拥有此属性。因此，如果您至少有1.5加三角洲，
so delta might be 5%, 10%, 2%, it depends how much sampling you do, but basically,
因此，达美航空可能是5％，10％，2％，这取决于您进行的抽样数量，但基本上是
if you have at least 1.5 plus delta of honest validators, so maybe 55% of the validator set
如果您至少有1.5加上诚实验证器的三角洲，则可能是验证器集的55％
is honest, it's a bit stronger than the honest majority assumption, then a majority always votes
老实说，这比诚实多数假设强一些，那么多数总是投票
against an available block and this against here is in the sense of block slot so it's going to
在可用的块上，这是在块插槽的意义上，所以它将
vote for the empty block rather than for this unavailable block um and basically so what this
投票给空块，而不是为这个不可用的块投票，基本上是这样
amounts to is a delta weakening of the uh you know of our assumptions so instead of assuming honest
总结是您知道我们的假设的UH的三角洲，而不是假设诚实
majority we have to assume honest majority plus delta um and or like delta strengthening or
多数我们必须承担诚实多数加上三角洲的多数，或者像增强三角洲或
assumptions and uh but if we do have that then we are sure that we can never accrue a majority
假设和嗯，但是如果我们确实有这样的假设
on an unavailable block. And once you have block slot, so by itself, this doesn't give you so much
在一个不可用的块上。一旦您拥有块插槽，所以本身，这不会给您太多
because even blocks that don't have a lot of votes, they're not supported by majority,
因为即使没有很多选票的障碍，他们也不受到多数的支持，
they can still be canonical or look canonical if you don't know that the block is actually
如果您不知道该块实际上是规范或外观
unavailable. But yeah, with the block slot for choice, it means that even if you are in this
不可用。但是，是的，有了可以选择的块插槽，这意味着即使您在此中
delta, even if you are one of the minority validators that has been fooled, that thinks
三角洲，即使您是被愚弄的少数派验证者之一，也认为
that this block is unavailable, sorry, that this block is available while it's not available.
抱歉，该块不可用，而该块在不可用的情况下可用。
With the block-sled fork choice, you still will not see it as canonical, because basically
有了块状叉子的选择，您仍然不会将其视为规范，因为基本上
everyone else, like the, you know, 1-delta people that are actually in the right, like
像你知道的其他人一样
that have not been fooled, they will come dragging with them.
没有被愚弄的，他们会和他们一起拖走。
Like, they are a majority, and they will put their weight on the empty block and make sure
就像，他们是多数人，他们会将自己的体重放在空块上，并确保
that you also go with them. And so basically, yeah, like the fork choice ends up working as
你也和他们一起去。因此，基本上，是的，就像叉子选择最终一样
if we just didn't have DAS, because if something is unavailable, then it can never look canonical
如果我们只是没有DAS，因为如果某物不可用，那么它永远不会看起来很典型
to anyone. Like you might vote for it right as it's proposed, because at that point, you don't
给任何人。就像您可能会按照提议的那样投票，因为那时您没有
know other people, like people haven't voted yet. You just, if it's there and it looks available to
认识其他人，例如人们还没有投票。您只是在那里，看起来可以
you, you vote for it. So if your sampling completes, you're going to vote for it. But then from the
您，您投票给它。因此，如果您的采样完成，您将投票。但是从
it's always going to look unavailable to you, as long as there is an honest majority.
只要有诚实的多数，它总是看起来不可能。
You will see that everyone voted for the empty slot, or a majority did, the honest people,
您会看到，每个人都投票赞成空位，或者大多数人都这样做，诚实的人，
and so you'll just go to the empty slot, part of the of the Fortress 3, and will just
因此，您只会进入“要塞3的一部分”的空插槽
say, okay, this looks available to me, but whatever, no one is voting for it, so I'm
说，好吧，这对我来说可用，但是无论如何，没有人投票给它，所以我
just going to go away from it. And this actually simplifies things a lot, it means that all of
只是要离开它。这实际上简化了很多事情，这意味着所有
all of these like weird edge cases which I didn't get into of like basically attacks that you can do
所有这些都像怪异的边缘案例，我没有像您一样攻击您可以做的
to try to exploit uh this minority of people that you can convince uh that something is unavailable
试图利用这少数人，您可以说服您不可用
and so on you can't actually do any of these attacks um so it it really makes things uh much
因此，您实际上不能进行任何这些攻击，所以它确实使事情变得很大
much nicer so that's and this is also again something um as I said before like block slot
更好，所以这也是我之前所说的，就像块插槽一样
it's like, it has this problem of back-off,
就像，它有一个退缩问题，
but I think it has a lot of advantages,
但是我认为它具有很多优势，
and I think this is probably the biggest advantage.
我认为这可能是最大的优势。
The ePBS thing is maybe it's nice,
EPB的事情也许很好，
but also I guess there's disagreement
但我想有分歧
around what exactly we should do with ePBS
围绕我们应该用EPB做什么
or whether or not it's needed,
还是是否需要
and different people tell you different things.
不同的人告诉你不同的事情。
I think everyone agrees that peer-to-us
我认为每个人都同意同伴到美国
is something that we really want to do,
是我们真正想做的事情，
and I think right now it looks to me
我想现在看着我
as if this block-slot-for-choice
好像这是一个选择的选择
it's a pretty important piece of it that really makes everything work nicely.
这是一个非常重要的一部分，确实使一切正常。
So that's why it's a higher value item to work on, potentially.
因此，这就是为什么它可能是更高的价值项目。
So again, it's pretty simple thing to think about.
因此，考虑一下这很简单。
You don't need a lot of background, I think.
我认为您不需要很多背景。
So that's maybe something that, yeah, if anyone that's following it just looks interested,
所以，也许是的，如果关注它的人看起来很感兴趣，
we can talk about it more.
我们可以更多地谈论它。
And I think, yeah, that's it.
我想，是的。
I know this was a lot.
我知道这很多。
I tried to give you just a sprinkling of a lot of things.
我试图给你很多东西。
And maybe you can go and watch the recording for details
也许您可以去看录音以获取详细信息
that I'm sure you've missed about a lot of stuff.
我敢肯定，您错过了很多东西。
But yeah, hopefully it gave you just an idea
但是，是的，希望它给你一个主意
of what are the main places in the roadmap
路线图的主要位置是什么
where the fork choice shows up at the moment,
目前出现的叉子选择的地方，
what are some of the long-term, what does it look like
长期有什么样的
the SSF landscape looks like.
SSF景观看起来像。
And again, there as well, I kind of, there's a lot that I didn't cover because there's multiple papers, just a lot of ongoing work.
再说一次，我也有很多我没有介绍的，因为有多个论文，只是许多持续的工作。
But yeah, I guess maybe in terms of like ways to get involved, as I said, like there is this specking effort that's sort of on and off happening around this like chained fast finality protocol.
但是，是的，我想也许就参与的方式而言，就像我所说的那样，就像有这种斑点的努力是在这种情况下和关闭的那样，就像链接的快速终结协议一样。
it's written but it could be written more nicely,
它写了，但可以写得更漂亮，
Luca is writing a paper around that, it's a formal document,
卢卡（Luca）正在围绕它写一篇论文，这是一份正式文件
but there's even a well-written blog post,
但是，甚至还有一篇写得很好的博客文章，
there's something that someone could do as well,
有人可以做的事情，
there's a lot of really small and big things to work on,
有很多很小的事情要做，
on a lot of these items, so yes, if you find anything interesting,
在许多这些项目上，是的，如果您发现任何有趣的东西，
and just shoot me a message, I guess.
我想只是给我发信息。
I, yeah, I'm not sure what's,
我，是的，我不确定是什么，
I guess on Discord it probably is what works best,
我想在不和谐上可能是最好的作用，
but, and then I guess I'll share,
但是，然后我想我会分享的，
I shared some resources in the GitHub thing,
我在github的东西中分享了一些资源，
but there's a lot more.
但是还有更多。
So maybe, yeah, I might leave some things,
所以也许，是的，我可能会留下一些东西，
but also just if someone is specifically interested
但也只是某人特别感兴趣
in a topic, then I can send you a lot more things.
在一个主题中，我可以向您发送更多东西。
I don't want to like inundate people with links.
我不想喜欢带有链接的人。
So yeah, that's that.
是的，就是这样。
Thank you for having me.
谢谢你有我。
Thank you very much, Francesco.
非常感谢，弗朗切斯科。
Yeah, thanks a lot.
是的，非常感谢。
This was a lot.
这很多。
I don't know it was, I can speak quite fast.
我不知道是，我可以说很快。
Yeah, still trying to process everything.
是的，仍在尝试处理所有内容。
It was a great talk though.
虽然这是一个很棒的演讲。
Thank you very much.
非常感谢。
One question is if you can join the Discord
一个问题是您是否可以加入不和谐
and maybe answer some questions later
也许以后回答一些问题
because people will probably watch it.
因为人们可能会观看它。
I will show you the link right here.
我将在这里向您展示链接。
Thank you very much. Let's see if there are any quick questions before we wrap it up in the last five minutes.
非常感谢。让我们看看在过去五分钟内将其包装好之前，是否有任何快速问题。
There was a question regarding the EPBS part now in the end.
现在有一个关于EPB的问题的问题。
In the blog slot slides, is the EPBS referring to block auction EPBS?
在博客插槽幻灯片中，EPB指的是Block Auction EPBS吗？
or does it change it?
还是它改变了？
Yeah, it's...
是的，是...
Yeah, like, basically,
是的，基本上，
what kind of EPBS design is this?
这是什么样的EPB设计？
Yeah, so the slides are referring
是的，所以幻灯片正在引用
to block auction EPBS,
为了阻止拍卖EPB，
like the most basic kind of original EPBS,
就像最基本的原始EPB一样，
but it doesn't really matter.
但这并不重要。
Like, slot auction,
就像，插槽拍卖，
it seems like it simplifies things,
似乎它简化了事情，
like, particularly if you know it in advance,
像，特别是如果您事先知道它，
like this auction has happened in advance.
像这样的拍卖已经事先发生了。
And so the builder really, you can tell in advance
因此，建造者确实可以提前告诉
who the builder is supposed to be.
建造者应该是谁。
But as far as I'm aware it doesn't actually
但是据我所知，实际上并不是
it turns out to simplify things that much
原来简化了很多东西
and you pretty much run into the same problems.
而且您几乎遇到了同样的问题。
But again, this is something where
但是，这再次是
there could definitely be more work.
肯定可以有更多的工作。
I don't know it's something that I've thought a lot
我不知道这是我想的很多
about it various times in the past
过去的各个时期
but I've never actually even like, you know
但是我从来没有真正喜欢过，你知道
gotten around to really writing something
到处写一些东西
formal about it, it's just a lot of things to do. So that's something that someone could
正式，这只是很多要做的事情。所以这是某人可以的
surely work on and write a nice blog post. There's a lot of space for clarifying some of these ideas,
肯定会撰写并写一篇不错的博客文章。有很多空间可以澄清其中一些想法，
but as far as I'm aware, they're both running into the same issues.
但是据我所知，他们都遇到了同样的问题。
Okay, thanks so much. Okay, yeah, off-topic question, what is it like being a researcher?
好吧，非常感谢。好吧，是的，主题问题，成为一名研究人员感觉如何？
What was it like for you to get to this role? You do a lot of research, a lot of amazing stuff,
您扮演这个角色是什么感觉？您进行了很多研究，很多很棒的事情，
so maybe if you can just share a little bit about your journey,
因此，也许如果您只能分享一些有关旅程的信息，
how did you end up working on the cutting edge of the consensus?
您最终是如何在共识的最前沿工作的？
it was pretty, I don't know, it's not something that I really expected, I just got in touch
很漂亮，我不知道，这不是我真正期望的，我只是在联系
with Justin at some point, because I was just really interested in Ethereum and wanted to
在某个时候，有了贾斯汀，因为我只是对以太坊真的很感兴趣，并想
see what it looks like to do research on these things, I guess it's maybe some European people
看看对这些事情进行研究的样子，我想也许是一些欧洲人
are listening that you have the same thoughts now um and uh at the time there was a lot of
正在听你现在有相同的想法，嗯，嗯，当时有很多
um interesting mv but also not a lot of like you know formal work done on it like there might not
嗯，有趣的MV，但也没有很多您知道在此上完成的正式工作
even have been like really i mean there was like a kind of seminal paper uh on it uh but and then
甚至真的像是真的，我的意思是有一种像一本开创性的纸上的嗯，然后
like some blog posts but not that much more so it seemed like oh you know this is an area where like
就像一些博客文章一样，但不多
clearly there's lack of work and it really just was a matter of someone just thinking about these
显然缺乏工作，这实际上只是有人只是在考虑这些
things. You didn't need who knows what background, you're just dedicating time to it. So I worked on
事物。您不需要谁知道什么背景，您只是在花时间。所以我从事
that for a little bit. There was a lot of interesting problems. Then in the course of
有一点。有很多有趣的问题。然后在
working on that it turned out it interacted a lot with consensus things and also a lot of this stuff
事实证明，它与共识的事物相互作用，还有很多这些东西
that I showed you at the beginning around Santa Rheorgs
我在圣诞老人Rheorgs开头给你看了
and whatever, it's a colleague of mine, Caspar,
无论如何，这是我的同事Caspar，
and Barnaby, which I guess you guys should know
和barnaby，我想你们应该知道
from the presentation, or just generally,
从演讲，或一般而言
they were working on it, because a lot of these issues
他们正在努力，因为很多这些问题
were very relevant at the time.
当时非常重要。
All these Rheorg things were real,
所有这些Rheorg都是真实的，
they could happen in the protocol.
它们可能发生在协议中。
And so I kind of got involved with that as well.
因此，我也有点参与其中。
I started combining the two things,
我开始结合两件事，
and yeah, basically summed this stuff around,
是的，基本上总结了这些东西，
like committee enforceable properties it shows up in member like that's some of
像委员会可强制执行的财产一样，它出现在会员中
the things I was working on like early and I kind of just realized that all you
我很早就从事的事情，我只是意识到你们所有人
know this portrait stuff is really a mess
知道这个肖像的东西真的是一团糟
there's like clearly a need for people to spend again time on it there is like
显然，人们需要再次花时间在上面
kind of lack of resources and yeah so it just seemed like well let's jump in into
有点缺乏资源，是的，好像让我们跳入
this thing where work is like really needed so I guess yeah it's been like a
这件事确实需要工作，所以我想是的
lot of time to my principal just try to figure out it like I'm not always trying
我的校长有很多时间尝试弄清楚它，就像我并不总是在尝试
to do something that I have who knows what kind of background for, because a lot of times
做我知道什么样的背景的事情，因为很多时候
it's not really that necessary.
并不是那么必要。
You just have to dig deep into something and read up as much as you can on it and figure
您只需要深入研究并尽可能多地阅读并弄清楚
out where the problems are.
解决问题的位置。
And it's not rocket science.
这不是火箭科学。
You sit down and write this stupid diagram that I showed you and eventually figure out
你坐下来写这张我向你展示的愚蠢图，最终弄清楚
something.
某物。
So it turns out that, yeah, a lot of times just looking at where is the need for problem solving is more important than maybe looking at what's my background.
因此，事实证明，是的，很多时候只是看解决问题的需求比看我的背景更重要。
Or at least that's kind of how it's been for me.
或者至少这对我来说是什么样的。
But, yeah, of course it can depend.
但是，是的，当然可以取决于。
I'm not saying just go fishing for random problems, but just, yeah, I think take into account where the need for problems to be solved is, as opposed to where there's already like 10 people that are trying to do something.
我并不是说只是出于随机问题去钓鱼，但是，是的，我认为要考虑到解决问题的需要是，而不是已经有10个人试图做某事的地方。
And in Ethereum, we don't have so many people doing research.
在以太坊中，我们没有那么多人进行研究。
So there's a lot of these areas where someone just showing up
因此，有很多这样的领域有人刚刚出现
and writing a hackmd might be, well,
写hackmd可能是
it turns out that in two months, you've
事实证明，在两个月内，您
become the expert on this thing.
成为这件事的专家。
JAVIER ARCHUELOVICH- Awesome.
哈维尔Archuelovich-很棒。
Thank you so much, Francesco.
非常感谢，弗朗切斯科。
I think it's a great motivation for people to end a call with.
我认为这是人们结束电话的巨大动力。
And yeah, we are right to the 90 minutes,
是的，我们是90分钟的正确
so we should get it up here.
因此，我们应该在这里启动它。
Again, thank you very much.
再次，非常感谢。
Appreciate it.
感谢它。
get a lot of content to digest to go through to report on the wiki um we yeah we keep up with this
获取很多内容要消化以进行Wiki UM报告，我们会跟上这一点
epf wiki and uh if anyone wants to document all the ssf and all the uh all the new info about the
EPF Wiki和UH，如果有人想记录所有SSF以及所有有关该信息的新信息
consensus we learned today there it would be really great i think it's a lot of work to write
我们今天在那里学到的共识，这真的很棒，我认为这是很多工作
about um yeah and uh yeah before we before we finish um i want to invite you folks on uh monday
关于嗯，是的，是的，在我们完成之前，我想在星期一邀请你们
we will have around at the same time we will have the wrap-up call after so this this with this call
在此之后，我们将在同一时间进行总结电话，所以此通话
we are finishing the study group um it's uh officially over but we'll have another more
我们正在完成研究小组，嗯，它正式结束了，但我们还有另一个
informal chat on monday around the same time so you all um are listening to this are invited
周一大约在同一时间，非正式聊天，所以大家都在听这件事
and yeah uh sorry for keeping you up long francesco thank you so much again it was really
是的，很抱歉让您保持漫长的Francesco再次感谢您
great and yeah uh please do uh join the discord uh if there is uh uh um if there's anything people
太好了，是的，嗯
will bother you with some questions if you didn't like it.
如果您不喜欢它，会打扰您一些问题。
Sure.
当然。
Thank you very much.
非常感谢。
Again, thanks for inviting me.
再次感谢您邀请我。
Sorry if I spoke fast, but it was wanting
对不起，如果我说话很快，但是它想要
to cover a lot of things, even if it might mean that people
涵盖很多东西，即使这可能意味着人们
need to rewatch it, some of it.
需要重新观看其中的一些。
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
是的，是的。
There's a lot of things that I'm interested in people
有很多我对人感兴趣的事情
working on, potentially.
继续进行。
Yeah, I think it's great.
是的，我认为这很棒。
This is what I was hoping to have in the study group.
这就是我希望在研究小组中拥有的东西。
But seeing your presentation with over 110 slides
但是看到您的110张幻灯片的演示文稿
you showed it i was thinking how can he how can he manage to fit in all of this but you did so
您展示了我在想他如何才能设法适应所有这些，但是您这样做了
yeah a lot of them were just transitions to be fair but yeah yeah that's right that's right but
是的，很多人只是过渡是公平的，但是是的，是的，没错，但是
still like uh i i also tend to speak it fast and i really respect this approach so yeah uh thank
仍然像嗯，我也倾向于快速说话，我真的很尊重这种方法，所以是的，谢谢
you so much again man uh have a great day yeah you too bye everyone bye everyone
你们又有很多
you
你